<MapDescriptions>
  <Map Key="Driver wish">
    <Title>Driver Wish (Wunschmenge)</Title>
    <Description>The Driver Wish map is the primary interface between the driver and the engine management system. It translates the accelerator pedal position (0-100%) and current engine speed (RPM) into a requested torque or Injected Quantity (IQ). This map defines the 'character' of the vehicle's response to throttle inputs. In EDC15P systems, this request is passed through various filters and limiters before becoming the actual injection command. It is the first step in the 'Mengenberechnung' (Quantity Calculation) chain described by Bosch.</Description>
    <UseCase>Used to define how the car feels during daily driving and wide-open throttle (WOT) conditions. It allows the tuner to request more fuel than the factory calibration originally intended.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Increase values in the high-pedal (70-100%) and high-RPM areas to request more power. Avoid increasing low-pedal areas to maintain smooth drivability in traffic. Ensure the requested IQ does not exceed the physical limits of the injectors or the safety limiters like the Torque Limiter.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Torque limiter">
    <Title>Torque Limiter (Drehmomentbegrenzung)</Title>
    <Description>The Torque Limiter is a safety-critical map that acts as a hard ceiling for the maximum fuel injection allowed at any given RPM and atmospheric pressure. Its primary function is to protect the mechanical components of the drivetrain from excessive stress. Bosch logic uses this map to ensure that the engine does not produce more torque than the clutch, dual-mass flywheel (DMF), and gearbox can safely handle. It also accounts for atmospheric pressure to protect the turbocharger from over-speeding at high altitudes where the air is thinner.</Description>
    <UseCase>This is typically the first limiter a tuner must modify to allow the engine to produce more power. Without increasing this, any increases in the Driver Wish map will be ignored by the ECU.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Increase the values to allow for higher torque, but do so with extreme caution. Avoid large increases below 2500 RPM to prevent 'clutch slip' or 'DMF shudder,' which can lead to premature hardware failure. Always maintain a downward slope at very high RPMs to provide a natural safety rev-limit.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Smoke limiter">
    <Title>Smoke Limiter (Rauchbegrenzung)</Title>
    <Description>The Smoke Limiter ensures that the engine maintains a proper Air-Fuel Ratio (AFR) to prevent the production of black smoke (soot). It limits the Injected Quantity (IQ) based on the actual air mass (MAF) or boost pressure (MAP) entering the cylinders. If the driver requests more fuel than there is air to burn it completely, this map steps in to reduce the injection. This is essential for meeting emission standards and keeping the exhaust gas temperatures (EGT) within safe limits. Bosch refers to this as the 'Rauchkennfeld'.</Description>
    <UseCase>Essential when increasing power to ensure the car remains 'smoke-free'. It is also adjusted when switching from MAF-based to MAP-based fueling (MAF-less tuning).</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Adjust this map to maintain an AFR of approximately 17:1 or 18:1 for a clean burn. If the car produces black smoke under acceleration, the values in this map are likely too high for the available air mass. Always coordinate changes here with increases in the Boost Target map.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Boost target">
    <Title>Boost Target Map (Ladedrucksollwert)</Title>
    <Description>This map defines the desired turbocharger boost pressure (in mbar) for a given engine speed and fuel injection quantity. The ECU uses this as the 'setpoint' for the boost control loop. By requesting higher pressure, the tuner provides more oxygen to the engine, allowing for more fuel to be burned efficiently without smoke. The Bosch 'Ladedruckregelung' logic compares this target against the actual pressure measured by the MAP sensor and adjusts the N75 duty cycle accordingly.</Description>
    <UseCase>Modified whenever more power is desired. Higher boost allows for higher fuel limits in the Smoke Limiter map.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Increase boost pressure gradually and stay within the 'compressor map' limits of the specific turbocharger installed. For factory GT1749V turbos, stay below 2500mbar (absolute) to avoid over-speeding the turbine. Ensure that the requested boost can be physically achieved by the hardware at the requested RPM.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="N75 duty cycle">
    <Title>N75 Duty Cycle (Ladedrucksteller)</Title>
    <Description>The N75 map controls the pulse-width modulation (PWM) signal sent to the vacuum solenoid that moves the Variable Nozzle Turbine (VNT) vanes. These vanes change the geometry of the turbocharger to speed up or slow down the turbine wheel. This map provides the 'pre-control' or 'feed-forward' values, allowing the ECU to position the vanes close to where they need to be before the PID controller fine-tunes the position. Proper calibration is vital for stable boost pressure and quick turbo spool-up.</Description>
    <UseCase>Adjusted to fix boost control issues such as 'boost spikes' (overshoot) or 'boost lag' (slow spool). It is also necessary when upgrading to a larger turbocharger with different vane characteristics.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>If you experience a boost spike, increase the duty cycle values (open the vanes more) in the area where the spike occurs. If the boost is slow to build, decrease the values (close the vanes more) to catch the exhaust gas more aggressively. Small changes (1-3%) are usually sufficient.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Start of injection">
    <Title>Start of Injection (SOI / Förderbeginn)</Title>
    <Description>The SOI map determines the exact moment the injectors begin spraying fuel into the combustion chamber, measured in degrees before Top Dead Center (BTDC). Timing is critical because it dictates how much time the fuel has to mix with air and burn. As engine speed increases, the time available for combustion decreases, requiring the injection to start earlier (advance). Bosch logic uses multiple SOI maps selected based on engine coolant temperature to ensure reliable starting and efficient operation across all thermal conditions.</Description>
    <UseCase>Advanced timing is often required when injecting larger quantities of fuel to ensure the combustion ends at the optimal point for torque production. It also helps in reducing exhaust gas temperatures (EGT).</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Advance timing carefully. Too much advance increases peak cylinder pressure significantly, which can damage head gaskets or pistons. Generally, do not exceed 28-30 degrees BTDC on PD engines without significant hardware reinforcement. Always monitor engine 'clatter' as an indicator of excessive advance.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Injector duration">
    <Title>Injector Duration (Förderdauer)</Title>
    <Description>The Duration map defines how long (in crankshaft degrees) the injector must remain open to deliver a specific quantity of fuel (IQ) at a given engine speed. This is a calibration map that describes the physical flow characteristics of the fuel injectors. In PD (Pumpe Düse) engines, the injection pressure is generated by the camshaft, so the duration must account for the varying pressure available at different RPMs. Bosch refers to this as the 'Förderdauerberechnung'.</Description>
    <UseCase>This map is primarily modified when the physical fuel injectors are replaced with larger ones (e.g., Firad +50% or +100% nozzles). It 're-scales' the ECU's understanding of fuel flow.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>This is not a 'power' map. It should only be changed to match the hardware. If you have stock injectors, do not touch this map. If you have larger nozzles, you must decrease the duration values because the larger holes flow more fuel in the same amount of time.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="BIP">
    <Title>BIP (Begin of Injection Period)</Title>
    <Description>BIP stands for 'Begin of Injection Period' and is a specialized calibration map for PD injectors. It accounts for the electrical and mechanical delay between the ECU sending a signal to the injector solenoid and the actual start of the needle movement. The ECU monitors the 'BIP signal' (a voltage spike) to detect exactly when the solenoid closes. This map provides the expected values for this delay, allowing the ECU to compensate for variations in battery voltage and fuel temperature.</Description>
    <UseCase>Adjusted when the engine has difficulty idling smoothly or when very large injectors are installed that have different solenoid response times.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Most tuners leave this map stock. Only modify it if you are an expert dealing with high-end performance injectors and have logs showing significant BIP deviation. Incorrect values here will cause the ECU to miscalculate the actual SOI and Duration, leading to poor engine performance.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="SVBL">
    <Title>SVBL (Single Value Boost Limiter)</Title>
    <Description>The SVBL is the final 'safety net' in the boost control system. Unlike the Boost Limit Map, which is a 3D table, the SVBL is a single constant value. If the actual boost pressure exceeds this value for more than a few seconds, the ECU immediately cuts fuel and enters 'Limp Mode' to protect the turbocharger and engine from catastrophic failure. It is the absolute maximum pressure the ECU will tolerate before taking emergency action.</Description>
    <UseCase>Must be increased whenever the Boost Target map is tuned to a level near or above the factory SVBL setting.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Set the SVBL approximately 50-100mbar higher than the highest value in your Boost Target map. This provides enough 'headroom' for small, temporary boost spikes without triggering Limp Mode, while still providing protection against a stuck VNT mechanism or a failed N75 valve.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="EGR">
    <Title>EGR Map (Abgasrückführung)</Title>
    <Description>The Exhaust Gas Recirculation (EGR) map controls the amount of exhaust gas that is fed back into the intake manifold. This process lowers the combustion temperature, which significantly reduces the production of Nitrogen Oxides (NOx). The map is indexed by engine speed and injected quantity. At idle and light loads, the EGR valve is open; at high loads and high RPMs, it is closed to allow for maximum fresh air and power. Bosch logic uses the MAF sensor to verify that the correct amount of air is being displaced by exhaust gas.</Description>
    <UseCase>Frequently modified by tuners to 'delete' or 'disable' the EGR system. This prevents oily carbon deposits from clogging the intake manifold and improves throttle response.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>To disable the EGR, set all values in the map to the maximum possible air mass (usually 850 or 1000 mg/stroke). This tells the ECU that it always wants maximum fresh air, effectively keeping the EGR valve closed at all times. Note that this may be illegal for road use in some jurisdictions.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="PID">
    <Title>PID Boost Controller (Proportional-Integral-Derivative)</Title>
    <Description>The PID maps (P, I, and D) are the mathematical parameters used by the ECU to fine-tune the boost pressure. While the N75 map provides a 'guess' at the vane position, the PID controller looks at the error (the difference between Target Boost and Actual Boost) and makes rapid corrections. 'P' (Proportional) reacts to the current error, 'I' (Integral) reacts to the accumulation of past errors to ensure the target is eventually met, and 'D' (Derivative) reacts to the speed at which the error is changing to prevent overshooting.</Description>
    <UseCase>Modified when the boost control is unstable despite a well-tuned N75 map. This is common with very large hybrid turbochargers that have much more inertia than stock units.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Tuning PID is complex. If the boost oscillates (waves up and down), you may need to reduce the 'P' or 'I' gains. If the boost never quite reaches the target, you may need to increase the 'I' gain. Most tuners should focus on the N75 map first, as it is much easier to calibrate and often solves 90% of boost control issues.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Linearization">
    <Title>Sensor Linearization Map</Title>
    <Description>Linearization maps are the 'translation tables' the ECU uses to understand raw electrical signals from sensors. For example, a MAP sensor sends a voltage between 0V and 5V. The Linearization map tells the ECU that 1V equals 500mbar and 4V equals 3000mbar. These maps are fundamental to the ECU's ability to perceive the physical world. There are linearization maps for the MAF sensor, MAP sensor, and various temperature sensors (Coolant, Fuel, Intake Air).</Description>
    <UseCase>Modified when hardware sensors are upgraded. A common upgrade is replacing the stock 3-bar MAP sensor with a 4-bar sensor to allow the ECU to 'see' boost pressures above 2000mbar (relative).</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Only change these if you have changed the physical sensor. You must use the specific calibration data provided by the sensor manufacturer (e.g., Bosch or VDO). Entering incorrect values here will cause the ECU to have a completely false understanding of engine conditions, which can lead to immediate engine damage.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Launch control map">
    <Title>Launch Control Map (Fahrverhalten)</Title>
    <Description>In EDC15P systems, Launch Control is often implemented by repurposing the 'Torque moment driving behavior map' (mrwFGFVHKF) or applying a patch to the Torque Limiter. It allows the engine to maintain a specific RPM (e.g., 2500 RPM) while stationary with the clutch depressed, enabling optimal boost build-up for a standing start. Bosch logic typically uses vehicle speed (VzuN) and gear detection to determine when to apply these specific torque limits.</Description>
    <UseCase>Used in performance tuning to allow for consistent and aggressive standing starts without excessive wheel spin or engine bogging.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Set the torque limit to a low value (or zero) at the desired launch RPM for vehicle speeds below 5 km/h. Ensure the transition back to full torque is smooth as vehicle speed increases to avoid drivetrain shock. Coordinate with the SVRL if a 'popcorn' or 'hard' limiter effect is desired.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="IQ by MAP limiter">
    <Title>IQ by MAP Limiter (Ladedruckabhängige Rauchbegrenzung)</Title>
    <Description>This map (Bosch code mroBEG_P) is an alternative smoke limiter that uses Manifold Absolute Pressure (MAP) instead of Air Mass (MAF) to calculate the maximum allowable fuel injection. This is the core of 'MAF-less' tuning. It ensures that the Injected Quantity (IQ) stays within a safe Air-Fuel Ratio (AFR) based on the actual boost pressure. The ECU selects between MAF and MAP limiting based on the 'cowBEG_P_L' configuration switch.</Description>
    <UseCase>Essential for vehicles where the MAF sensor has been removed or is being bypassed. It provides a more robust fueling calculation in high-performance setups where MAF sensors often become a restriction or fail.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Calibrate this map to maintain an AFR of 17:1 or 18:1. Since boost pressure is a proxy for air mass, you must account for volumetric efficiency. If the values are too high, the engine will produce excessive soot before the turbocharger reaches full boost.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Boost limit map">
    <Title>Boost Limit Map (Ladedruckbegrenzung)</Title>
    <Description>The Boost Limit Map is a 3D safety table that defines the maximum permissible boost pressure based on engine speed (RPM) and atmospheric pressure (mbar). Its primary purpose is to protect the turbocharger from over-speeding. At high altitudes (low atmospheric pressure), the turbo must spin much faster to achieve the same boost level; this map reduces the allowed boost to keep the turbine within its physical structural limits.</Description>
    <UseCase>Modified when installing a larger turbocharger or increasing boost targets. It acts as a continuous safety ceiling below the SVBL.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Always set the values in this map slightly higher (approx. 50-100mbar) than the 'Boost Target' map, but significantly lower than the turbocharger's burst limit. Ensure the limit decreases as atmospheric pressure drops to protect the hardware during mountain driving.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Limit of overboost protection (zmwVEPLSKF)">
    <Title>Overboost Protection Limit (Ladedrucküberwachung)</Title>
    <Description>This characteristic (zmwVEPLSKF) defines the maximum allowed deviation between the target boost and the actual boost before the ECU triggers a protection intervention. Bosch logic monitors this 'Regelabweichung' (control deviation). If the actual boost exceeds the target by more than this limit for a duration defined by the debouncing timer (zmwVETSuKF), the ECU will reduce injection or enter limp mode.</Description>
    <UseCase>Adjusted to prevent 'nuisance' limp mode triggers on high-performance setups with aggressive spool-up or large hybrid turbos that may have slight overshoot.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Increase this value slightly if you experience limp mode during rapid gear changes or initial spool-up, but do not disable it. It is a vital safety feature that prevents engine damage in the event of a stuck VNT mechanism or failed N75 valve.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Start IQ">
    <Title>Start IQ (Startmenge)</Title>
    <Description>The Start IQ maps (mrwSTMGRKF and mrwSTMGxKF) determine the amount of fuel injected during the engine cranking phase. The quantity is indexed by engine coolant temperature and cranking RPM. Bosch logic provides higher fuel quantities at low temperatures to overcome internal friction and ensure a quick start. Once the engine reaches the 'Startabwurfdrehzahl' (start-off speed), the ECU transitions to the Driver Wish and Idle control logic.</Description>
    <UseCase>Modified to fix 'hot start' issues common on older PD engines where the starter motor no longer reaches the factory-required RPM, or to improve cold starting in extreme climates.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>To fix hot start issues, increase the IQ values in the high-temperature (70°C+) and low-RPM (150-250 RPM) regions. Avoid excessive increases at low temperatures, as this can cause heavy smoke or 'diesel knock' immediately after starting.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="SVRL (Single Value Rev Limiter)">
    <Title>SVRL (Single Value Rev Limiter)</Title>
    <Description>The SVRL is a single constant value that acts as the absolute electronic engine speed ceiling. When the engine speed reaches this value, the ECU immediately cuts fuel injection. Unlike the Torque Limiter, which provides a gradual reduction in power, the SVRL is a 'hard' limit. In EDC15P, this is often found near the Torque Limiter sequence.</Description>
    <UseCase>Used to set a safe maximum RPM for the engine or to create a 'popcorn' / 'hard' rev limiter effect for performance applications.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Set this value to the maximum safe RPM for your valvetrain (e.g., 5200-5500 RPM on stock PD engines). For a 'popcorn' limiter, set the SVRL to the desired RPM and ensure the Torque Limiter does not taper off too early, allowing the engine to hit the hard cut-off.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Fuel Temperature overheating protection (mrwBKT_KF)">
    <Title>Fuel Temperature Overheating Protection (mrwBKT_KF)</Title>
    <Description>This safety map monitors the fuel temperature (anmKTF) and reduces the maximum allowable injection quantity if the fuel becomes too hot. High fuel temperatures reduce the lubricity of the diesel, which can lead to premature wear or seizure of the high-pressure pump and injectors. Bosch logic uses this as a 'component protection' measure.</Description>
    <UseCase>Protects the fuel system hardware during extreme operating conditions or in the event of a failing fuel cooler.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Generally, these values should not be increased. If you are experiencing power loss due to fuel temperature, investigate the cooling system rather than raising the limits. In extreme performance builds with upgraded cooling, slight adjustments may be made to prevent nuisance power cuts.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Oil temperature overheat protection (mrwBOEL_KF)">
    <Title>Oil Temperature Overheat Protection (mrwBOEL_KF)</Title>
    <Description>This map limits the injected quantity based on engine oil temperature. As oil temperature rises beyond safe operating limits, the ECU reduces engine load to prevent thermal runaway and mechanical failure. It is a critical part of the Bosch 'Motorschutz' (Engine Protection) strategy.</Description>
    <UseCase>Prevents catastrophic engine damage if the cooling system is overwhelmed or fails.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Do not modify this map unless you have installed significantly upgraded oil cooling and are monitoring temperatures with high-precision external sensors. Lowering these limits can provide an extra layer of safety for track-driven vehicles.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Injection correction map (Height)">
    <Title>Injection Correction Map - Atmospheric Pressure (fnwSWSN_KF)</Title>
    <Description>This map adjusts the start of injection (SOI) or delivery based on the current atmospheric pressure (ldmADF). At higher altitudes, the air is thinner, which changes the combustion characteristics. This correction ensures that the engine remains efficient and emissions-compliant regardless of elevation.</Description>
    <UseCase>Maintains drivability and prevents excessive smoke when driving in mountainous regions.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Usually left stock. If tuning for a specific high-altitude environment, small adjustments can be made to optimize timing for the lower air density.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Injection correction map (Air Temperature)">
    <Title>Injection Correction Map - Intake Air Temperature (anwLTF_KL)</Title>
    <Description>This characteristic corrects the injection quantity or timing based on the intake air temperature (IAT). Hotter air is less dense, meaning less oxygen is available for combustion. The ECU uses this map to trim the fueling to maintain the desired Air-Fuel Ratio and protect against high Exhaust Gas Temperatures (EGT).</Description>
    <UseCase>Protects the engine from leaning out or overheating in hot weather or during prolonged high-load operation.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>If you have installed a much larger intercooler, you may need to adjust this map to account for the improved cooling efficiency. Always ensure that the EGTs remain within safe limits after modification.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Water temperature dependent load IQ increase (mrwBWT_KF)">
    <Title>Coolant Temp Dependent IQ Increase (mrwBWT_KF)</Title>
    <Description>This map provides an additional fuel quantity based on engine coolant temperature (anmWTF). It is primarily used during the warm-up phase to compensate for the higher internal friction of a cold engine and to ensure stable combustion until the engine reaches operating temperature.</Description>
    <UseCase>Ensures smooth engine operation and prevents stalling during the transition from cold start to fully warm.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>If the engine feels 'sluggish' or stumbles during the warm-up phase, small increases here can improve drivability. Avoid large increases as they will lead to excessive fuel consumption and potential smoke while the engine is cold.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="ARD Ramp rate load change - positive (mrwFPRA_KF)">
    <Title>ARD Positive Ramp Rate (Anti-Jerk Filter)</Title>
    <Description>The Active Anti-Jerk Filter (ARD) uses this map to control the maximum rate of increase for the injected quantity during rapid throttle applications. It smooths out the transition to prevent mechanical oscillations in the drivetrain, known as 'bucking' or 'jerking'. Bosch refers to this as the 'Führungsformer'.</Description>
    <UseCase>Adjusted to sharpen the engine's response to throttle inputs. Higher values allow for faster torque build-up.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Increase values carefully to improve throttle 'snap'. If increased too much, the car may become difficult to drive smoothly in low gears, as every small pedal movement will cause a sharp surge in torque.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="ARD Ramp rate load change - negative (mrwFNRA_KF)">
    <Title>ARD Negative Ramp Rate (Anti-Jerk Filter)</Title>
    <Description>This map controls the rate at which fuel is reduced when the driver lifts off the accelerator. Similar to the positive ramp, it prevents the engine from 'dropping' too quickly, which can cause uncomfortable drivetrain lash and vibrations.</Description>
    <UseCase>Modified to achieve a more natural engine braking feel or to prevent 'clunking' during rapid lift-off.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Decrease values to allow for faster engine braking. If the lift-off feels too abrupt or causes drivetrain noise, increase the values to slow down the fuel reduction ramp.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="AG4 Transmission upshift map (mrwM_EH_KF)">
    <Title>AG4 Transmission Upshift Torque Map</Title>
    <Description>This map defines the torque characteristics or limits communicated to the AG4 automatic transmission controller during an upshift. It ensures that the engine and gearbox are synchronized to provide a smooth gear change without excessive clutch wear or shift shock.</Description>
    <UseCase>Critical for vehicles with automatic transmissions to ensure shift quality is maintained after an engine power increase.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>If the transmission 'slips' or shifts too slowly after tuning, you may need to adjust these values to match the new engine torque curve. Always coordinate changes with the transmission control unit (TCU) calibration if possible.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Load impact detection speed/gear - Positive (mrwDLS_pos)">
    <Title>Load Impact Detection - Positive (mrwDLS_pos)</Title>
    <Description>This map detects sudden positive load changes based on engine speed and current gear. It triggers the ARD intervention logic when it senses a 'load impact' that could lead to drivetrain oscillations. Bosch logic uses this to distinguish between intentional acceleration and unwanted jerking.</Description>
    <UseCase>Used to fine-tune the sensitivity of the anti-jerk system for different driving conditions and gear ratios.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Usually left stock. If the anti-jerk system is too intrusive (cutting power when you want it), you can increase the detection thresholds. If the car jerks excessively, lower the thresholds to trigger the damping logic earlier.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Torque moment driving behavior map (mrwFGFVHKF)">
    <Title>Torque Driving Behavior Map (Fahrverhalten)</Title>
    <Description>This map defines the dynamic torque request based on the driver's pedal input and engine speed. It is a 'shaping' map that influences how the engine transitions between different load states. In many EDC15P tuning scenes, this map is the primary target for implementing Launch Control patches by setting specific limits at zero vehicle speed.</Description>
    <UseCase>Modified to change the 'feel' of the accelerator pedal or to implement custom features like Launch Control or No-Lift Shift.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>For Launch Control, set the torque to a very low value at the desired launch RPM for the lowest speed axis. For general driving, adjust the slope to make the pedal feel more linear or more aggressive depending on preference.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="EGR PWM Basic Map (arwSTTVKF)">
    <Title>EGR PWM Basic Map (arwSTTVKF)</Title>
    <Description>This map defines the base pulse-width modulation (PWM) duty cycle for the EGR solenoid valve. It provides the 'pre-control' values for the EGR valve position based on engine speed and injected quantity. Bosch logic uses this to set the initial valve opening before the closed-loop MAF-based controller takes over.</Description>
    <UseCase>Used to physically control the EGR valve. Tuners often modify this map when deleting the EGR system to ensure the valve remains closed under all conditions.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>To disable the EGR, set the duty cycle values to the state that corresponds to a fully closed valve (usually 0% or 95% depending on the solenoid type). This ensures the valve does not open even if the setpoint map is modified.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Airmass backup values map (arwLMVGWKF)">
    <Title>Airmass Backup Values (arwLMVGWKF)</Title>
    <Description>This map provides substitute air mass values that the ECU uses if the Mass Air Flow (MAF) sensor signal is lost or determined to be implausible. It allows the engine to continue running in a 'limp home' mode by estimating air mass based on engine speed and boost pressure.</Description>
    <UseCase>Safety fallback for sensor failure. Also relevant when tuning 'MAF-less' setups to ensure the ECU has a reasonable baseline for fueling calculations.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Usually left stock. If you have significantly modified the engine's volumetric efficiency (e.g., different camshafts or ported head), you may need to update these values to ensure the car remains drivable if the MAF sensor fails.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Air mass calculation air temp/pressure (arwLMBKOKF)">
    <Title>Air Mass Correction - Temp/Pressure (arwLMBKOKF)</Title>
    <Description>This map corrects the calculated air mass based on intake air temperature and atmospheric pressure. Since air density changes with temperature and altitude, this correction is vital for the ECU to accurately determine the actual oxygen content available for combustion.</Description>
    <UseCase>Ensures consistent fueling and smoke control across different environmental conditions.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Critical for high-boost applications. If you are running boost levels far beyond stock, ensure this map is calibrated to account for the higher intake temperatures often seen at the limit of the turbocharger's efficiency.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="EGR Air linearization map (arwLMBLIKL)">
    <Title>EGR Air Linearization (arwLMBLIKL)</Title>
    <Description>This characteristic linearizes the air mass signal for the EGR control loop. It translates the raw sensor data into a format that the PID controller can use to accurately maintain the EGR setpoint.</Description>
    <UseCase>Calibration map for the EGR feedback system.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Do not modify unless you have changed the MAF sensor to a different type with different flow characteristics. Incorrect linearization will cause the EGR system to oscillate or fail to reach its target.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="EGR shutdown threshold - upper (arwMEAB1KL)">
    <Title>EGR Shutdown Threshold - Upper (arwMEAB1KL)</Title>
    <Description>This characteristic defines the upper injection quantity threshold above which the EGR system is automatically deactivated. At high loads, the engine requires maximum fresh air for power and to keep EGTs low, so the ECU closes the EGR valve.</Description>
    <UseCase>Ensures EGR does not interfere with full-load performance.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>If you want the EGR to turn off earlier as load increases, lower these thresholds. This can improve throttle response during the transition to high load.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Boost correction by water temperature (ldwTW_KF)">
    <Title>Boost Correction - Coolant Temp (ldwTW_KF)</Title>
    <Description>This map adjusts the target boost pressure based on the engine coolant temperature. It is a safety feature that reduces turbocharger load when the engine is either too cold (to prevent mechanical stress) or too hot (to prevent overheating).</Description>
    <UseCase>Protects the turbocharger and engine during extreme thermal conditions.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Usually left stock. If you are building a dedicated track car, you may want to make the boost reduction more aggressive at high temperatures to provide an extra safety margin.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Boost pressure correction (ldwTVPAKF)">
    <Title>Boost Correction - Atmospheric Pressure (ldwTVPAKF)</Title>
    <Description>This characteristic corrects the boost pressure target based on the ambient atmospheric pressure. As altitude increases and air becomes thinner, the turbocharger must spin faster to maintain the same boost level. This map reduces the boost request at high altitudes to prevent the turbo from exceeding its maximum safe RPM.</Description>
    <UseCase>Ensures turbocharger longevity when driving in high-altitude environments.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Critical for high-boost setups. If you have upgraded to a larger turbo with a higher speed rating, you may be able to relax these limits slightly, but always stay within the manufacturer's compressor map.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Boost shutdown freezing time (ldwVZDZ_KL)">
    <Title>Boost Shutdown Delay (ldwVZDZ_KL)</Title>
    <Description>This characteristic defines the 'freezing time' or delay before the ECU triggers a boost-related shutdown or limp mode. It allows for temporary boost spikes (overshoot) during rapid transients without immediately cutting power.</Description>
    <UseCase>Prevents nuisance limp mode triggers during aggressive driving or gear changes.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>If you are experiencing limp mode during initial spool-up despite a well-tuned N75 map, increasing this delay slightly can help. However, do not set it too high, as it also delays protection in the event of a genuine boost control failure.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Boost pressure control ON threshold (ldwREG1KL)">
    <Title>Boost Control Activation Threshold (ldwREG1KL)</Title>
    <Description>This characteristic defines the engine speed or load threshold where the ECU's closed-loop boost control (PID) becomes active. Below this threshold, the turbocharger is typically in an 'open-loop' state where the vanes are in a fixed position for spool-up.</Description>
    <UseCase>Ensures the boost controller only operates when the turbocharger is capable of reaching the target pressure.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>If you have installed a much larger turbo that spools later than stock, you may need to increase this threshold to prevent the PID controller from 'winding up' before the turbo is ready.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Radiator fan-caster correction map (kuwNLKORKF)">
    <Title>Radiator Fan After-Run Correction (kuwNLKORKF)</Title>
    <Description>This map adjusts the radiator fan speed or duration during the after-run phase (after the engine is turned off). It is indexed by engine temperature and ambient temperature to ensure that the engine bay is sufficiently cooled to prevent heat soak and protect sensitive components.</Description>
    <UseCase>Ensures thermal stability after high-load operation.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Usually left stock. In high-performance builds where heat soak is a major concern, the after-run duration or fan speed can be increased to help dissipate heat more effectively after a run.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Electric cooling fan basic speed map (kuwElGRDKF)">
    <Title>Electric Fan Basic Speed Map (kuwElGRDKF)</Title>
    <Description>This map defines the base duty cycle or speed for the electric cooling fans relative to the engine coolant temperature. It is the primary control table for the vehicle's active cooling system during engine operation.</Description>
    <UseCase>Modified to trigger cooling fans earlier or at higher speeds in hot climates or for track-focused vehicles.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Lowering the temperature thresholds can help keep the engine in its optimal thermal window during aggressive driving. Ensure the electrical system can handle the increased load if fans are set to run at 100% duty cycle frequently.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Glow plugs glow control map (gswTV4_KF)">
    <Title>Glow Plug Control Map (gswTV4_KF)</Title>
    <Description>This map controls the pulse-width modulation (PWM) duty cycle sent to the glow plugs. It determines the intensity and duration of the heating phase based on the engine coolant temperature. Proper glow plug operation is essential for reducing cranking time and emissions during a cold start.</Description>
    <UseCase>Critical for reliable starting in extreme cold conditions.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>If the vehicle struggles to start in very cold weather despite healthy glow plugs, the duty cycle or duration can be increased. Avoid excessive heating as it will significantly shorten the lifespan of the glow plugs.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Air compressor switch-off time - min (klwTMIN_KF)">
    <Title>AC Compressor Min Switch-Off Time (klwTMIN_KF)</Title>
    <Description>This characteristic defines the minimum time the air conditioning compressor must remain off once it has been deactivated. This 'anti-cycling' logic protects the AC clutch and compressor from mechanical damage caused by rapid engagement and disengagement.</Description>
    <UseCase>Protects the AC system hardware during aggressive driving where the ECU may frequently cut the AC load.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Do not decrease this value. Increasing it can provide additional protection if the AC system is showing signs of premature wear in a tuned vehicle.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Air conditioning torque requirement (mrwKLMD_KF)">
    <Title>AC Torque Compensation (mrwKLMD_KF)</Title>
    <Description>This map estimates the mechanical torque load (in Nm) that the AC compressor places on the engine. The ECU uses this value to adjust the idle speed controller and the anti-jerk logic, ensuring that the engine does not stumble or stall when the AC clutch engages.</Description>
    <UseCase>Maintains idle stability and drivability when the air conditioning is active.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Usually left stock. If you have installed a non-standard AC compressor or have significantly lightened the flywheel, you may need to adjust these values to maintain a smooth idle.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="MAF linearization">
    <Title>MAF Sensor Linearization (arwLMLIN_KL)</Title>
    <Description>This characteristic line defines the relationship between the voltage signal from the Hot Film Air Mass (HFM) sensor and the actual air mass flow in mg/h. It is the primary scaling table for the MAF sensor.</Description>
    <UseCase>Used when replacing the stock MAF sensor with a different model (e.g., upgrading to a larger housing or a different sensor generation) to ensure the ECU correctly calculates the incoming air mass.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Do not modify unless the physical sensor or its housing has been changed. Incorrect scaling will lead to inaccurate smoke limiting and poor drivability.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="MAP linearization">
    <Title>MAP Sensor Linearization (ldwPLIN_KL)</Title>
    <Description>This line scales the voltage output of the Manifold Absolute Pressure (MAP) sensor into physical pressure units (mbar). It typically defines the 0V and 5V (or 0.5V to 4.5V) limits of the sensor.</Description>
    <UseCase>Essential when upgrading from a standard 2.5-bar or 3-bar sensor to a 4-bar sensor to support higher boost levels. Without updating this, the ECU will under-report boost, leading to overboost and potential turbo failure.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Ensure the values match the datasheet of the installed sensor. Common 4-bar sensors (e.g., Bosch 0281002576) require specific scaling to report pressure accurately.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Water temperature sensor linearization">
    <Title>Coolant Temperature Sensor Linearization (anwWTF_KL)</Title>
    <Description>Converts the raw voltage/resistance from the Engine Coolant Temperature (ECT) sensor into degrees Celsius. This sensor influences almost every ECU calculation, including start IQ, glow plugs, and fan control.</Description>
    <UseCase>Used if a non-standard temperature sensor is fitted or to verify sensor accuracy across the operating range.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Generally should not be touched. If the engine is reporting incorrect temperatures despite a new sensor, verify the wiring and pull-up resistor logic before adjusting this table.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Intake manifold temp sensor linearization (anwSTF_KL)">
    <Title>Intake Manifold Temperature Linearization (anwSTF_KL)</Title>
    <Description>Scales the intake air temperature sensor. This value is used for air density calculations and boost pressure corrections (ldwTVTLKL).</Description>
    <UseCase>Calibration for custom intake setups or different sensor types.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Accurate intake temp readings are vital for safety limiters. Ensure this matches the physical sensor characteristics.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Speed dependent - IQ limit in case of error (mrwBEM_KL)">
    <Title>Emergency IQ Limit (mrwBEM_KL)</Title>
    <Description>This characteristic line defines the maximum allowed injection quantity (IQ) when a critical sensor error is detected (e.g., MAF or MAP failure). It acts as a "limp home" safety limit.</Description>
    <UseCase>Adjusted to provide slightly more power in limp mode or to further restrict the engine if a specific hardware failure is high-risk.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Keep these values conservative to protect the engine during a fault condition.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="VCDS Diagnostic IQ Limit (1-10)">
    <Title>Diagnostic IQ Display Limit</Title>
    <Description>This single value defines the maximum injection quantity that can be displayed via diagnostic protocols (K-Line/VCDS). It does not limit the actual injection, only the reported value.</Description>
    <UseCase>Increased when tuning for high power (e.g., >70mg) so that the actual injected quantity can be monitored in VCDS logs without being clipped at the stock limit.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Set this slightly higher than your maximum requested IQ in the Torque Limiter.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="BIP - Basic voltage linearization map (zmwBPGndKL)">
    <Title>BIP Voltage Compensation (zmwBPGndKL)</Title>
    <Description>This characteristic line compensates for the electrical latency of the PD injector solenoid based on the vehicle's battery voltage. At lower voltages, the solenoid takes longer to reach the 'pull-in' current required to move the injector needle.</Description>
    <UseCase>Calibration for high-performance injectors or when dealing with electrical system variations. It ensures the ECU's timing remains precise even during voltage drops.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Usually left stock. If upgrading to injectors with significantly different solenoid characteristics, this map must be recalibrated to prevent timing drift.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="BIP - Fuel temperature correction curve (zmwBPKorKL)">
    <Title>BIP Fuel Temperature Correction (zmwBPKorKL)</Title>
    <Description>Adjusts the expected BIP (Begin of Injection Period) signal based on fuel temperature. Changes in fuel temperature affect the viscosity and density of the fuel, which in turn alters the mechanical response time of the injector needle.</Description>
    <UseCase>Ensures consistent injection timing across the full operating temperature range of the fuel system.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Do not modify unless you have precise test-bench data for your specific injectors. Incorrect values will lead to 'timing jitter' and unstable idle as the fuel warms up.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Selector for start of injection map (fnwSWGK_KL)">
    <Title>SOI Map Selector (fnwSWGK_KL)</Title>
    <Description>This selector line determines which of the multiple Start of Injection (SOI) maps the ECU uses at any given moment. The selection is primarily driven by engine coolant temperature, allowing the ECU to switch from 'cold start' timing to 'warm' timing.</Description>
    <UseCase>Used to identify which SOI maps are active during specific temperature windows. Tuners use this to ensure they are modifying the correct map for the current engine state.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Essential for verifying that your timing changes will actually be applied. If you modify SOI Map 9 but the selector is pointing to Map 8 at operating temperature, your changes will have no effect.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Fuel volume correction map (zmwMKOR_KF)">
    <Title>Fuel Volume Correction (zmwMKOR_KF)</Title>
    <Description>A fine-tuning map that applies a correction factor to the injected quantity based on engine speed and temperature. It accounts for the thermal expansion of diesel fuel and the mechanical tolerances of the high-pressure pump system.</Description>
    <UseCase>Used to achieve perfect fueling accuracy across all RPM ranges. It can be used to 'trim' the fueling if the engine is consistently running slightly rich or lean compared to the requested IQ.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Only modify if you have verified the actual fuel flow via high-precision logging or a dyno. Small adjustments (1-2%) can help smooth out the torque curve.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="CVT Transmission drag torque limitation (mrwSchmxKF)">
    <Title>CVT Drag Torque Limit (mrwSchmxKF)</Title>
    <Description>This map limits the engine's drag torque (negative torque) during deceleration or shifting in vehicles equipped with a CVT (Continuously Variable Transmission). It protects the CVT belt and pulleys from the high mechanical stresses caused by rapid changes in engine speed.</Description>
    <UseCase>Critical for maintaining CVT longevity in tuned vehicles. It ensures that the engine does not 'pull' too hard against the transmission during lift-off.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Generally should be left stock. If the CVT is slipping during deceleration after a power increase, these limits may need to be tightened (reduced torque allowed).</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Motor mount control duty cycle (mlwTW_KF)">
    <Title>Active Motor Mount Control (mlwTW_KF)</Title>
    <Description>Controls the pulse-width modulation (PWM) signal sent to active (switchable) engine mounts. The ECU adjusts the stiffness of the mounts based on engine speed and coolant temperature to minimize the transmission of vibrations to the vehicle chassis, especially at idle.</Description>
    <UseCase>Used to restore factory-like refinement if the engine has become more 'vibrant' due to tuning or if aftermarket mounts are installed.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Tuners often leave this stock. However, if you experience excessive cabin vibration at specific RPMs, adjusting the duty cycle can help 'tune out' the resonance.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Acceleration limitation map (mrwBdn_KF)">
    <Title>Acceleration Gradient Limit (mrwBdn_KF)</Title>
    <Description>This map defines the maximum permissible rate of change for engine speed (dn/dt). It acts as a dynamic limiter that prevents the engine from accelerating too rapidly in a way that would cause drivetrain 'bucking' or exceed the physical limits of the transmission components.</Description>
    <UseCase>Used to smooth out the power delivery in low gears or to protect fragile drivetrain components (like CVT belts) from sudden torque spikes.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Increasing these values will make the engine feel more 'raw' and responsive, but at the cost of increased drivetrain stress. Decrease these values if the car feels jerky during rapid acceleration.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Deactivation of drag torque limitation (mrwRSch_KL)">
    <Title>Drag Torque Deactivation (mrwRSch_KL)</Title>
    <Description>A characteristic line that defines the threshold (usually based on vehicle speed or engine temperature) at which the drag torque limitation logic is deactivated. This allows the engine to return to normal braking behavior once the risk to the transmission is low.</Description>
    <UseCase>Fine-tuning the transition between protected shifting and normal engine braking.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Usually left stock. Only adjust if the transition feels unnatural or if the protection is staying active for too long.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Altitude dependent speed correction (mrwBATM_KF)">
    <Title>Altitude Speed Correction (mrwBATM_KF)</Title>
    <Description>This map adjusts the engine speed limits or targets based on the current atmospheric pressure. Its primary purpose is to protect the turbocharger from over-speeding at high altitudes, where the air is thinner and the turbine must spin faster to maintain boost.</Description>
    <UseCase>Ensures turbocharger longevity during mountain driving or in high-altitude regions.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Do not increase these values unless you have verified the turbocharger's maximum safe RPM at low air densities. Reducing these values can provide an extra safety margin for high-boost setups.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Altitude dependent - SOI Pressure selector (fnwSWAD_KL)">
    <Title>SOI Altitude Selector (fnwSWAD_KL)</Title>
    <Description>A characteristic line that selects the appropriate Start of Injection (SOI) correction or base map based on atmospheric pressure. It ensures that the injection timing is optimized for the lower oxygen content and different combustion characteristics found at high altitudes.</Description>
    <UseCase>Maintains engine efficiency and prevents excessive smoke when driving in elevated environments.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Usually left stock. If the engine feels sluggish or produces excessive smoke only at high altitudes, small timing advances may be calibrated here.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Altitude dependent - Smoke turbo boost pos ramp (mrwTSADpKL)">
    <Title>Altitude Smoke Ramp - Positive (mrwTSADpKL)</Title>
    <Description>Defines the maximum rate of increase (positive ramp) for the smoke limiter's fueling allowance as atmospheric pressure changes. It smooths the transition of the smoke limiter logic during rapid altitude changes to prevent sudden bursts of soot.</Description>
    <UseCase>Fine-tuning the 'cleanliness' of the exhaust during mountain climbs.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Lowering these values will make the smoke limiter more conservative during altitude transitions, reducing soot at the cost of slightly slower response.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Altitude dependent - Smoke turbo boost neg ramp (mrwTSADnKL)">
    <Title>Altitude Smoke Ramp - Negative (mrwTSADnKL)</Title>
    <Description>Controls the rate of decrease (negative ramp) for fueling limits when atmospheric pressure drops. This ensures that the engine does not continue to inject 'sea level' quantities of fuel when the available air mass has decreased due to altitude.</Description>
    <UseCase>Protects the engine from running too rich and producing excessive EGTs at high altitudes.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Ensure these values allow for a rapid enough reduction in fuel to protect the engine if you are driving into significantly thinner air.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Engine temp dependent - Starter motor disengage (mrwSTNB_KL)">
    <Title>Starter Disengagement Threshold (mrwSTNB_KL)</Title>
    <Description>This characteristic line defines the engine speed (RPM) at which the ECU determines the engine has successfully started and signals the starter motor to disengage. The threshold is higher at lower temperatures to ensure the engine has enough momentum to sustain combustion against high internal friction.</Description>
    <UseCase>Modified if the starter motor disengages too early (causing the engine to stall) or too late (causing a grinding noise) after a performance build or in extreme climates.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Usually left stock. If you have installed a high-torque starter or a lightened flywheel, you may need to adjust these RPM thresholds to ensure reliable starting.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Engine temp dependent - Starter motor after-time (mrwSTNO_KL)">
    <Title>Starter Phase After-Time (mrwSTNO_KL)</Title>
    <Description>Defines a temperature-dependent duration (in seconds) after the engine has reached the disengagement speed during which the ECU maintains 'Start IQ' logic. This ensures a smooth transition from cranking to idling by preventing a sudden drop in fueling.</Description>
    <UseCase>Used to fix 'stumble' issues that occur immediately after the engine fires but before it settles into a stable idle.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Small increases can help stabilize the engine if it feels weak immediately after starting. Avoid large increases as it will lead to unnecessary fuel consumption and potential smoke.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Engine temperature-dependent idle start speed (mrwLLW_KL)">
    <Title>Initial Idle Speed Offset (mrwLLW_KL)</Title>
    <Description>Sets the target idle speed immediately following a successful start, based on coolant temperature. A higher initial idle helps the engine reach operating temperature faster and ensures stable oil pressure during the first few seconds of operation.</Description>
    <UseCase>Adjusted to improve cold-start refinement or to provide a more aggressive 'fast idle' for track cars that need rapid warm-up.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Ensure the transition from this speed to the steady-state idle (Target Idle Speed Map) is smooth. Setting this too high can cause excessive wear on a cold engine.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Glowplug control - Indicator glow period (gswGAZ_KL)">
    <Title>Glow Plug Lamp Duration (gswGAZ_KL)</Title>
    <Description>This characteristic line defines how long the glow plug indicator lamp (the 'coil' symbol) remains illuminated on the dashboard relative to the coolant temperature. Note that the actual heating of the glow plugs often continues after the lamp goes out (after-glow).</Description>
    <UseCase>Modified to give the driver a more accurate indication of when the engine is ready to be cranked in cold weather.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>If you have upgraded to faster-heating ceramic glow plugs, you can reduce these times. For standard plugs in very cold climates, increasing the lamp time ensures the driver waits long enough for sufficient heat build-up.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="EGR shutdown threshold - upper (arwMEAB1KL)">
    <Title>EGR Shutdown Threshold - Upper (arwMEAB1KL)</Title>
    <Description>This characteristic line defines the upper injection quantity (IQ) threshold above which the EGR system is automatically deactivated. At high loads, the engine requires maximum fresh air for power and to keep exhaust gas temperatures (EGT) low, so the ECU closes the EGR valve.</Description>
    <UseCase>Used to ensure the EGR does not interfere with full-load performance or to turn off the EGR earlier in the load range for improved throttle response.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Lowering these values will cause the EGR to shut off at lower loads. This is often done as part of a partial EGR delete to keep the intake cleaner while maintaining some emissions benefits at light cruise.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="EGR shutdown threshold - lower (arwMEAB0KL)">
    <Title>EGR Shutdown Threshold - Lower (arwMEAB0KL)</Title>
    <Description>Defines the injection quantity threshold for reactivating the EGR system after it has been shut down. This creates a hysteresis loop with the upper threshold (arwMEAB1KL) to prevent the EGR valve from rapidly 'cycling' or oscillating at a specific load point.</Description>
    <UseCase>Fine-tuning the stability of the EGR system during load transitions.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Always ensure these values are lower than the corresponding values in the upper threshold map to maintain a stable hysteresis window.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Air mass calculation air temp/pressure (arwLMBKOKF)">
    <Title>Air Mass Correction - Temp/Pressure (arwLMBKOKF)</Title>
    <Description>This map corrects the calculated air mass based on intake air temperature and atmospheric pressure. Since air density changes with temperature and altitude, this correction is vital for the ECU to accurately determine the actual oxygen content available for combustion, especially in 'MAF-less' (MAP-based) fueling modes.</Description>
    <UseCase>Ensures consistent fueling and smoke control across different environmental conditions and boost levels.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Critical for high-boost applications. If you are running boost levels far beyond stock, ensure this map is calibrated to account for the higher intake temperatures often seen at the limit of the turbocharger's efficiency.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="EGR Air linearization map (arwLMBLIKL)">
    <Title>EGR Air Mass Linearization (arwLMBLIKL)</Title>
    <Description>This characteristic line linearizes the air mass signal specifically for the EGR feedback control loop. It translates raw sensor data into a format that the EGR PID controller can use to accurately maintain the requested EGR setpoint.</Description>
    <UseCase>Calibration map for the EGR feedback system.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Do not modify unless you have changed the MAF sensor to a different type with different flow characteristics. Incorrect linearization will cause the EGR system to oscillate or fail to reach its target.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Map - time for delayed shutdown (arwTi_abKL)">
    <Title>EGR Delayed Shutdown Timer (arwTi_abKL)</Title>
    <Description>Defines a temperature-dependent delay time before the EGR system is completely shut down after a trigger condition (such as prolonged idling) is met. This prevents the EGR from staying active indefinitely when the vehicle is stationary, which can lead to intake clogging.</Description>
    <UseCase>Adjusted to change how long the EGR remains active during idle.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Reducing these times can help keep the intake manifold cleaner by shutting off the EGR sooner when the car is not moving.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Injector dynamic advance selector map (fnwSWDY_KL)">
    <Title>Dynamic Advance Selector (fnwSWDY_KL)</Title>
    <Description>This characteristic line determines the activation or weighting of dynamic injection advance during rapid load changes (transients). It ensures that the injection timing is advanced quickly enough to support sudden increases in torque request, preventing 'timing lag' during acceleration.</Description>
    <UseCase>Used to sharpen the engine's response during rapid throttle applications.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Usually left stock. If the engine feels 'flat' during the first half-second of a WOT pull despite aggressive SOI maps, small adjustments here can trigger the advance logic more effectively.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Twisted camshaft torsion correction (zmwNWkoKL)">
    <Title>Camshaft Torsion Correction (zmwNWkoKL)</Title>
    <Description>Compensates for the physical twisting (torsion) of the camshaft under high load. In PD engines, the injection pressure is generated by the cam lobes; at high RPM and high IQ, the mechanical stress causes the cam to deflect slightly. This map corrects the solenoid timing to ensure the actual injection occurs at the intended crankshaft angle.</Description>
    <UseCase>Critical for maintaining timing accuracy in high-power builds where injection pressures are significantly higher than stock.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Do not modify unless you have performed high-resolution crank/cam angle logging and identified a consistent timing drift under load. Incorrect values will lead to 'jittery' timing and potential mechanical stress.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Selector for injector duration">
    <Title>Duration Map Selector</Title>
    <Description>This characteristic line selects which of the multiple Injector Duration maps is active based on the current Start of Injection (SOI). Since the cam lobe profile changes the available injection pressure over the timing window, the ECU must switch duration calibrations to maintain fueling accuracy.</Description>
    <UseCase>Used to identify which duration maps (e.g., Duration 0 through 5) are active at specific timing advance levels. Tuners use this to ensure they are modifying the correct duration table for their SOI targets.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Essential for verifying that your duration changes will actually be applied. If you are running 25 degrees of advance but the selector is pointing to a duration map calibrated for 15 degrees, your fueling will be inaccurate.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Injection advance at start map (fnwSWSTxKR)">
    <Title>Start Phase Injection Advance (fnwSWSTxKR)</Title>
    <Description>Defines the injection advance (SOI) specifically during the engine cranking and initial start phase. It is indexed by engine speed and coolant temperature to ensure optimal cylinder pressure for reliable ignition during cold and hot starts.</Description>
    <UseCase>Modified to improve starting reliability, especially in engines with modified compression ratios or non-standard injectors.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Small increases in advance can help cold starting in extreme conditions. Avoid excessive advance during cranking as it can cause 'kickback' against the starter motor.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="PID map - P amplification (ldwPRfakKL)">
    <Title>Boost PID - Proportional Gain (ldwPRfakKL)</Title>
    <Description>This characteristic line defines the Proportional (P) gain of the boost PID controller relative to engine speed. The P-term reacts immediately to the current boost error (Target vs. Actual). Higher gain makes the controller more aggressive but can lead to instability.</Description>
    <UseCase>Adjusted when the boost pressure is slow to react to target changes or when the boost oscillates rapidly around the target.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>If boost is 'lazy', increase P-gain slightly. If boost oscillates (hunts), decrease P-gain. Always tune the N75 pre-control map first before touching PID gains.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="PID map - I amplification (ldwIRfakKL)">
    <Title>Boost PID - Integral Gain (ldwIRfakKL)</Title>
    <Description>Defines the Integral (I) gain of the boost controller. The I-term accounts for the accumulation of past errors over time, ensuring that the boost pressure eventually reaches the exact target even if there is a steady-state offset.</Description>
    <UseCase>Used to eliminate 'steady-state error' where the boost pressure stays consistently below or above the target by a small amount.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Increase I-gain if the boost never quite reaches the target. Decrease it if the boost 'overshoots' and takes a long time to settle back down.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="PID map - D amplification (ldwDRfakKL)">
    <Title>Boost PID - Derivative Gain (ldwDRfakKL)</Title>
    <Description>Defines the Derivative (D) gain of the boost controller. The D-term reacts to the rate of change of the boost error, acting as a 'brake' to prevent the pressure from rising too quickly and overshooting the target.</Description>
    <UseCase>Critical for controlling 'boost spikes' during rapid spool-up or gear changes.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Increase D-gain to dampen boost spikes. Too much D-gain can make the boost control feel 'sluggish' or cause high-frequency jitter in the N75 duty cycle.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Boost actuator upper limit curve (ldwDRmaxKL)">
    <Title>N75 Actuator Upper Limit (ldwDRmaxKL)</Title>
    <Description>This characteristic line defines the maximum allowed duty cycle for the N75 solenoid across the RPM range. It acts as a hard ceiling for the PID controller, preventing the VNT vanes from being held in an extreme position that could cause mechanical binding or excessive exhaust backpressure.</Description>
    <UseCase>Modified when installing an aftermarket actuator or a turbocharger with different vane travel limits.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Ensure this limit is set high enough to allow full boost but low enough to prevent the actuator from 'bottoming out' or causing the turbo to choke the engine at high RPM.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="PID map - DT1 memory factor (ldwDR_gfKL)">
    <Title>Boost PID - D-Term Damping (ldwDR_gfKL)</Title>
    <Description>This characteristic line defines the 'memory' or damping factor for the Derivative (D) component of the PID controller. It smooths out the D-term calculation to prevent erratic vane movement caused by sensor noise or rapid pressure fluctuations.</Description>
    <UseCase>Fine-tuning the smoothness of the boost control loop, especially in high-vibration environments or with sensitive MAP sensors.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Usually left stock. If the N75 duty cycle logs show high-frequency 'noise' despite stable boost, increasing this damping factor can help smooth the actuator signal.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Radiator after-run pump time (kuwNLGRDKF)">
    <Title>Auxiliary Water Pump After-Run (kuwNLGRDKF)</Title>
    <Description>This map controls the operation time of the auxiliary electric coolant pump after the engine is turned off. It is indexed by engine coolant temperature and ambient temperature. Its purpose is to maintain coolant circulation to prevent 'hot spots' and localized boiling in the cylinder head after high-load operation.</Description>
    <UseCase>Ensures long-term reliability of the cylinder head and head gasket by managing heat soak after the engine stops.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Usually left stock. In high-performance builds or vehicles used for towing, increasing these times can help protect the engine from thermal stress after a hard run.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Generator load torque loss map (mrwDFMD_KF)">
    <Title>Alternator Torque Compensation (mrwDFMD_KF)</Title>
    <Description>Estimates the mechanical torque (in Nm) required to drive the alternator based on the electrical load (DF signal) and engine speed. The ECU uses this value to proactively adjust the injection quantity, ensuring that the idle speed remains stable when heavy electrical consumers (like seat heaters or window defrosters) are switched on.</Description>
    <UseCase>Maintains idle refinement and prevents the engine from 'dipping' or stumbling under electrical load.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Generally should not be touched. If you have installed a significantly higher-output alternator, this map may need adjustment to maintain perfect idle stability.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Oil level threshold map (mrwOELNiKF)">
    <Title>Dynamic Oil Level Thresholds (mrwOELNiKF)</Title>
    <Description>Defines the thresholds for the electronic oil level sensor to trigger a 'Low Oil' warning on the dashboard. The map accounts for engine speed and temperature, as oil level readings vary significantly depending on how much oil is currently circulating through the engine and its thermal expansion.</Description>
    <UseCase>Prevents false 'Low Oil' warnings during high-RPM driving or in extreme temperatures.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Do not modify. This is a critical safety monitoring map. If you are receiving false warnings, check the physical sensor and oil grade before considering software changes.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Engine Oil thermal load map (siwOEL_tKF)">
    <Title>Oil Thermal Aging Map (siwOEL_tKF)</Title>
    <Description>This map is part of the Bosch 'Wartungsintervallverlängerung' (WIV) or Flexible Service Interval logic. It calculates the thermal stress placed on the engine oil based on engine speed and load. The ECU integrates this 'thermal load' over time to determine the optimal point for the next oil change service.</Description>
    <UseCase>Used by the ECU to calculate the remaining life of the engine oil.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Tuners often leave this stock. However, if the engine is consistently run at much higher loads than factory (e.g., a track car), the ECU will naturally shorten the service interval based on the logic in this map.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Overboost debouncing limit (zmwVETSuKF)">
    <Title>Overboost Debouncing Timer (zmwVETSuKF)</Title>
    <Description>This map defines the time delay (in milliseconds) that an overboost condition must persist before the ECU triggers a protection intervention or limp mode. It acts as a 'filter' to prevent temporary boost spikes during rapid gear changes or initial spool-up from causing nuisance power cuts.</Description>
    <UseCase>Adjusted on high-performance setups with aggressive turbochargers that may have slight, harmless overshoot during transients.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Increase this value slightly if you are experiencing limp mode during gear changes despite a well-tuned N75 map. Do not set it too high, as it also delays protection in the event of a genuine boost control failure (e.g., a popped vacuum line).</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Map - Minimum IQ control upper threshold (zmwMEmi1KL)">
    <Title>Smooth Running Controller - Upper IQ Limit (zmwMEmi1KL)</Title>
    <Description>This characteristic line defines the upper injection quantity threshold for the Smooth Running Controller (LRR). The LRR balances cylinder-to-cylinder variations to ensure a smooth idle. Above this IQ threshold, the ECU stops attempting to balance the cylinders as the engine is no longer in a steady-state idle condition.</Description>
    <UseCase>Ensures the cylinder balancing logic does not interfere with normal driving or low-load cruising.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Usually left stock. If you have installed very large injectors that require a higher idle IQ, you may need to increase this threshold to keep the balancing logic active at the new idle point.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Map - Minimum IQ control lower threshold (zmwMEmi0KL)">
    <Title>Smooth Running Controller - Lower IQ Limit (zmwMEmi0KL)</Title>
    <Description>Defines the lower injection quantity threshold for the cylinder balancing logic. If the requested IQ drops below this value (e.g., during overrun), the balancing logic is deactivated to prevent unnecessary solenoid adjustments.</Description>
    <UseCase>Fine-tuning the activation window of the Smooth Running Controller.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Always ensure this value is lower than the upper threshold (zmwMEmi1KL) to maintain a stable operating window for the controller.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Map - Boundary acceleration limited quantity (mrwBdnN_KL)">
    <Title>Acceleration-Limited IQ Boundary (mrwBdnN_KL)</Title>
    <Description>This characteristic line defines the maximum allowable injection quantity when the engine is at its acceleration limit (dn/dt). It works in conjunction with the Acceleration Limitation Map to prevent the ECU from requesting excessive fuel during rapid RPM rises, which could lead to drivetrain oscillations or mechanical failure.</Description>
    <UseCase>Protects the drivetrain during rapid acceleration in low gears.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Increasing this value will allow for more power during rapid RPM rises, but at the cost of increased drivetrain stress. Set this to match the torque capacity of your transmission and axles.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Boost intake manifold vacuum detection (mrwLDFU_KL)">
    <Title>Intake Vacuum Detection Threshold (mrwLDFU_KL)</Title>
    <Description>In a turbocharged diesel engine, the intake manifold should rarely be under significant vacuum. This characteristic line defines the pressure threshold below which the ECU detects a 'vacuum' condition. This usually indicates a severely restricted air intake (e.g., a clogged filter) or a turbocharger failure.</Description>
    <UseCase>Diagnostic monitoring of the air intake system integrity.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Do not modify. This is a critical diagnostic threshold that helps identify hardware failures before they cause engine damage.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Hydraulic fan speed normalization (kuwHyLFTKF)">
    <Title>Hydraulic Fan Speed Normalization (kuwHyLFTKF)</Title>
    <Description>This map normalizes the speed request for hydraulic cooling fans. Since hydraulic fans are driven by an engine-mounted pump, their potential speed varies with engine RPM. This map ensures that the actual fan speed remains consistent with the ECU's cooling request regardless of how fast the engine is spinning.</Description>
    <UseCase>Calibration for vehicles equipped with hydraulic cooling systems (common in heavy-duty or specialized VAG applications).</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Usually left stock. If the cooling performance is inconsistent across the RPM range, this map may need adjustment to account for pump efficiency.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Water critical temperature basic map (kuwWTFkrKF)">
    <Title>Critical Coolant Temperature Thresholds (kuwWTFkrKF)</Title>
    <Description>Defines the 'critical' temperature limits for the engine coolant based on engine speed and load. When the coolant temperature exceeds these thresholds, the ECU enters an emergency cooling mode, triggering maximum fan speed and potentially reducing fuel injection (IQ) to prevent catastrophic overheating.</Description>
    <UseCase>Primary safety monitoring for the engine's thermal state.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Do not increase these values. These are hard safety limits designed to protect the engine block and head from warping or cracking due to extreme heat.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Electric fan speed characterization (kuwElLFTKL)">
    <Title>Electric Fan PWM Characterization (kuwElLFTKL)</Title>
    <Description>This characteristic line defines the relationship between the ECU's internal cooling request (0-100%) and the actual pulse-width modulation (PWM) duty cycle sent to the electric fan controller. It ensures that the fan motor reacts linearly to the ECU's demands.</Description>
    <UseCase>Used when replacing the stock cooling fans with aftermarket units that have different PWM response characteristics.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Adjust this if your aftermarket fans are not spinning at the expected speed for a given ECU request. Ensure the 100% request actually results in maximum fan speed.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Cooling fan speed correction curve (kuwANKORKL)">
    <Title>Fan Speed Vehicle Speed Correction (kuwANKORKL)</Title>
    <Description>Applies a correction factor to the cooling fan speed request based on the vehicle's forward speed. At higher speeds, the 'ram air' effect provides significant natural cooling, allowing the ECU to reduce the fan's electrical load without compromising engine temperatures.</Description>
    <UseCase>Energy management and noise reduction during high-speed cruising.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Usually left stock. If the engine tends to run hot only at high speeds, you may need to reduce the correction factor to keep the fans more active.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Gear-dependent torque limiters (mrwM_EBGxKL)">
    <Title>Gear-Dependent Torque/Quantity Limits (mrwM_EBGxKL)</Title>
    <Description>A series of characteristic lines (one for each gear) that define the maximum allowable torque or injection quantity. These are primarily used to protect the transmission and drivetrain components from excessive stress, particularly in lower gears where the torque multiplication is highest.</Description>
    <UseCase>Limiting torque in 1st and 2nd gear to prevent gearbox failure or excessive wheel spin.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>When increasing power, these limits must be raised proportionally. However, be cautious with 1st and 2nd gear limits to avoid stripping gears or damaging the differential.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="CVT-specific torque limit (mrwM_ECVTKL)">
    <Title>CVT Transmission Torque Limit (mrwM_ECVTKL)</Title>
    <Description>This characteristic line is specific to vehicles equipped with a Continuously Variable Transmission (CVT). It defines the maximum engine torque allowed to ensure the CVT belt does not slip and the variator pulleys are not overloaded.</Description>
    <UseCase>Drivetrain protection for CVT-equipped VAG models (e.g., early Multitronic systems).</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Exercise extreme caution. CVT transmissions are very sensitive to torque increases. Exceeding the factory limits often leads to rapid belt wear or total transmission failure.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Automated manual transmission limit (mrwM_EASGKL)">
    <Title>ASG/Automated Manual Torque Limit (mrwM_EASGKL)</Title>
    <Description>Defines the torque limits for Automated Manual Transmissions (ASG). This map is used by the ECU to coordinate torque reduction during automated gear shifts, ensuring smooth clutch transitions and protecting the internal shift actuators.</Description>
    <UseCase>Calibration of shift comfort and speed for ASG-equipped vehicles.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>If shifts feel 'jerky' after a tune, this map may need adjustment to allow for a smoother torque ramp-down and ramp-up during the shift phase.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="General transmission protection limit (mrwM_EGETKL)">
    <Title>TCU Requested Torque Limit (mrwM_EGETKL)</Title>
    <Description>A global torque limit requested by the Transmission Control Unit (TCU) via the CAN bus. This map defines how the ECU should respond to these external requests, typically used during gear changes or when the TCU detects a transmission over-temperature condition.</Description>
    <UseCase>Integration between the Engine ECU and Transmission ECU for drivetrain longevity.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Do not disable. This is the primary communication channel for the transmission to protect itself. If the TCU requests a limit, there is usually a valid mechanical reason.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Torque gradient limit (mrwM_EGRKL)">
    <Title>Torque Gradient Limit (mrwM_EGRKL)</Title>
    <Description>This characteristic line limits the maximum rate of change (gradient) for the engine torque. It prevents the engine from increasing or decreasing torque too rapidly, which protects the dual-mass flywheel, gearbox, and engine mounts from sudden mechanical shocks.</Description>
    <UseCase>Smoothing out the 'tip-in' and 'tip-out' behavior of the engine.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Increasing these values will make the engine feel more responsive and 'snappy,' but at the cost of increased drivetrain wear and potential 'jerky' behavior during rapid throttle changes.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Pedal value filter constant (mrwPWG_FIL)">
    <Title>Accelerator Pedal Signal Filter (mrwPWG_FIL)</Title>
    <Description>Defines the filtering intensity for the raw signal coming from the accelerator pedal sensor (PWG). It removes electrical noise and minor driver foot tremors to provide a clean, stable torque request to the ECU's calculation chain.</Description>
    <UseCase>Signal conditioning for the driver's primary input.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Usually left stock. Excessive filtering will cause a noticeable delay in throttle response, while too little filtering can lead to an unstable idle or 'twitchy' part-load behavior.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Anti-jerk damping gain (mrwM_EARD_K)">
    <Title>Anti-Jerk (ARD) Damping Intensity (mrwM_EARD_K)</Title>
    <Description>This map controls the gain or 'strength' of the Active Ruckeldämpfer (ARD) system. The ARD detects drivetrain oscillations (bucking) and applies rapid, micro-adjustments to the injection quantity to counteract and cancel out these vibrations.</Description>
    <UseCase>Eliminating drivetrain 'shudder' or 'bucking' during low-speed maneuvers or rapid gear changes.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>If the car feels like it's 'bouncing' after a heavy tune or clutch upgrade, this gain may need to be increased. However, setting it too high can cause the ECU to fight itself, leading to a loss of smoothness.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Transient smoothing map (mrwM_ESMOO)">
    <Title>Transient Load Smoothing (mrwM_ESMOO)</Title>
    <Description>A map used to manage the transition between different engine load states. It smooths the injection quantity delivery during the critical phase where the engine moves from a steady-state (like cruising) to a transient-state (like accelerating).</Description>
    <UseCase>Refining drivability and preventing 'stumbling' during part-load transitions.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Adjust this if the engine feels hesitant or 'flat' for a split second when you first touch the throttle. It helps bridge the gap between the driver's request and the turbocharger's response.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Start-off speed threshold (mrwSTNABKL)">
    <Title>Start-Off RPM Threshold (mrwSTNABKL)</Title>
    <Description>This characteristic line defines the engine speed (RPM) at which the ECU determines the engine has successfully fired and is now running under its own power. Once this threshold is crossed, the ECU exits the 'Start' phase and begins normal torque calculation.</Description>
    <UseCase>Fixing 'start-stall' issues where the ECU stops injecting start fuel before the engine has enough momentum to idle.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Usually left stock. If the engine fires but immediately dies during cold starts, increasing this threshold slightly can keep the Start IQ active for a few more RPMs to stabilize the combustion.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Starter motor cut-off time (mrwST_OFZ)">
    <Title>Maximum Cranking Duration (mrwST_OFZ)</Title>
    <Description>Defines the maximum time the ECU will allow the engine to crank without reaching the start-off speed. If this time limit is exceeded, the ECU will stop injecting fuel to protect the starter motor from overheating and the battery from excessive discharge.</Description>
    <UseCase>Safety limit for the electrical starting system.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Do not decrease this value in cold climates, as the engine may need longer cranking times to start. Increasing it can be useful if the engine is known to be a 'slow starter' due to hardware modifications.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Start quantity release delay (mrwSTMFRKL)">
    <Title>Start IQ Injection Delay (mrwSTMFRKL)</Title>
    <Description>A temperature-dependent delay that pauses fuel injection for a short period after the starter begins turning the engine. This delay allows the mechanical components to begin moving and oil pressure to start rising before the first combustion event occurs.</Description>
    <UseCase>Improving engine longevity by ensuring lubrication begins before the engine is subjected to combustion loads.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Usually left stock. Reducing this delay can result in a 'faster' perceived start, but at the cost of increased wear on a cold engine.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Boost-based cranking detection (mrwST_dPL)">
    <Title>Crank Sensor Diagnostic Threshold (mrwST_dPL)</Title>
    <Description>This diagnostic value monitors the change in boost pressure (MAP) while the engine is supposedly stationary (0 RPM). If the pressure fluctuates significantly, it implies the engine is actually turning but the crankshaft sensor is failing to report RPM.</Description>
    <UseCase>Diagnostic monitoring of the engine speed sensor integrity during the start phase.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Do not modify. This is a critical safety check that prevents the ECU from attempting to run the engine with a corrupted or missing RPM signal.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="EGR shutdown threshold - lower (arwMEAB0KL)">
    <Title>EGR Reactivation Threshold (arwMEAB0KL)</Title>
    <Description>Defines the injection quantity (IQ) threshold for reactivating the EGR system after it has been shut down due to high load. This works in conjunction with the upper threshold (arwMEAB1KL) to create a hysteresis loop, preventing the EGR valve from rapidly cycling on and off at a specific load point.</Description>
    <UseCase>Ensuring EGR system stability during load transitions.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Always keep these values lower than the corresponding values in the upper threshold map. If you have lowered the shutdown threshold for a partial EGR delete, you must lower this reactivation threshold proportionally.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Airmass backup values map (arwLMVGWKF)">
    <Title>Air Mass Plausibility & Backup (arwLMVGWKF)</Title>
    <Description>This map defines the expected air mass values for any given engine speed and boost pressure. The ECU uses this to verify the health of the MAF sensor. If the actual MAF reading deviates too far from these values, the ECU flags a fault and uses this map as a 'backup' to estimate air mass for smoke limiting.</Description>
    <UseCase>Diagnostic monitoring and 'MAF-less' fallback logic.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>If you have significantly modified the engine's breathing (e.g., big-valve head or performance camshafts), you may need to update this map to prevent false MAF sensor codes.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Air mass calculation air temp/pressure (arwLMBKOKF)">
    <Title>Air Mass Environmental Correction (arwLMBKOKF)</Title>
    <Description>Applies a correction factor to the air mass calculation based on intake air temperature and atmospheric pressure. This ensures that the ECU's internal model of air density remains accurate, which is critical for precise smoke limiting and EGR control in varying climates.</Description>
    <UseCase>Maintaining fueling accuracy across different altitudes and weather conditions.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Usually left stock. For extreme high-boost applications where intake temperatures are significantly higher than factory levels, this map may need calibration to ensure the smoke limiter remains effective.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Map - time for delayed shutdown (arwTi_abKL)">
    <Title>EGR Idle Shutdown Timer (arwTi_abKL)</Title>
    <Description>Defines a temperature-dependent delay time. If the engine idles for longer than this duration, the ECU automatically closes the EGR valve. This is a protective measure to prevent the intake manifold and EGR valve from becoming clogged with carbon deposits during prolonged stationary periods.</Description>
    <UseCase>Intake system protection during extended idling.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Reducing these times is a common 'stealth' modification to keep the intake cleaner without completely disabling the EGR system for emissions testing.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Injector dynamic advance selector map (fnwSWDY_KL)">
    <Title>Dynamic Injection Advance Selector (fnwSWDY_KL)</Title>
    <Description>This characteristic line determines the weighting or activation of dynamic injection advance during rapid load changes (transients). It ensures that the Start of Injection (SOI) is advanced quickly enough to support sudden increases in torque request, preventing 'timing lag' that could lead to poor combustion during acceleration.</Description>
    <UseCase>Sharpening the engine's response during rapid throttle applications.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Usually left stock. If the engine feels 'flat' during the first half-second of a pull despite aggressive SOI maps, small adjustments here can trigger the advance logic more effectively.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Injection advance at start map (fnwSWSTxKR)">
    <Title>Start Phase Injection Advance (fnwSWSTxKR)</Title>
    <Description>Defines the injection advance (SOI) specifically during the engine cranking and initial start phase. It is indexed by engine speed and coolant temperature to ensure optimal cylinder pressure for reliable ignition during both cold and hot starts.</Description>
    <UseCase>Improving starting reliability, especially in engines with modified compression ratios or non-standard injectors.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Small increases in advance can help cold starting in extreme conditions. Avoid excessive advance during cranking as it can cause 'kickback' against the starter motor.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Twisted camshaft torsion correction (zmwNWkoKL)">
    <Title>Camshaft Torsion Compensation (zmwNWkoKL)</Title>
    <Description>Compensates for the physical twisting (torsion) of the camshaft under high load. In PD engines, the injection pressure is generated by the cam lobes; at high RPM and high IQ, the mechanical stress causes the cam to deflect slightly. This map corrects the solenoid timing to ensure the actual injection occurs at the intended crankshaft angle.</Description>
    <UseCase>Maintaining timing accuracy in high-power builds where injection pressures are significantly higher than stock.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Do not modify unless you have performed high-resolution crank/cam angle logging and identified a consistent timing drift under load. Incorrect values will lead to 'jittery' timing and potential mechanical stress.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Fuel volume correction map (zmwMKOR_KF)">
    <Title>Fuel Volume Thermal Correction (zmwMKOR_KF)</Title>
    <Description>A fine-tuning map that applies a correction factor to the injected quantity based on engine speed and temperature. It accounts for the thermal expansion of diesel fuel and the mechanical tolerances of the high-pressure pump system, ensuring that the requested IQ matches the actual mass of fuel delivered.</Description>
    <UseCase>Achieving perfect fueling accuracy across all operating temperatures.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Only modify if you have verified the actual fuel flow via high-precision logging or a dyno. Small adjustments (1-2%) can help smooth out the torque curve as the engine warms up.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Generator load torque loss map (mrwDFMD_KF)">
    <Title>Alternator Torque Compensation (mrwDFMD_KF)</Title>
    <Description>Estimates the mechanical torque (in Nm) required to drive the alternator based on the electrical load (DF signal) and engine speed. The ECU uses this value to proactively adjust the injection quantity, ensuring that the idle speed remains stable when heavy electrical consumers (like seat heaters or window defrosters) are switched on.</Description>
    <UseCase>Maintains idle refinement and prevents the engine from 'dipping' or stumbling under electrical load.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Generally should not be touched. If you have installed a significantly higher-output alternator, this map may need adjustment to maintain perfect idle stability.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Air conditioning torque requirement (mrwKLMD_KF)">
    <Title>AC Torque Compensation (mrwKLMD_KF)</Title>
    <Description>This map defines the mechanical torque load placed on the engine by the air conditioning compressor. The ECU uses this value to adjust the idle speed controller and the anti-jerk logic, ensuring that the engine does not stumble or stall when the AC clutch engages or when refrigerant pressure is high.</Description>
    <UseCase>Maintains idle stability and drivability when the air conditioning is active.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Usually left stock. If you have installed a non-standard AC compressor or have significantly lightened the flywheel, you may need to adjust these values to maintain a smooth idle.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Motor mount control duty cycle (mlwTW_KF)">
    <Title>Active Motor Mount Control (mlwTW_KF)</Title>
    <Description>Controls the pulse-width modulation (PWM) signal sent to active (switchable) engine mounts. The ECU adjusts the stiffness of the mounts based on engine speed and coolant temperature to minimize the transmission of vibrations to the vehicle chassis, especially at idle.</Description>
    <UseCase>Used to restore factory-like refinement if the engine has become more 'vibrant' due to tuning or if aftermarket mounts are installed.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Tuners often leave this stock. However, if you experience excessive cabin vibration at specific RPMs, adjusting the duty cycle can help 'tune out' the resonance.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Air compressor switch-off time - min (klwTMIN_KF)">
    <Title>AC Compressor Min Switch-Off Time (klwTMIN_KF)</Title>
    <Description>This characteristic defines the minimum time the air conditioning compressor must remain off once it has been deactivated. This 'anti-cycling' logic protects the AC clutch and compressor from mechanical damage caused by rapid engagement and disengagement during high-load driving.</Description>
    <UseCase>Protects the AC system hardware during aggressive driving where the ECU may frequently cut the AC load.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Do not decrease this value. Increasing it can provide additional protection if the AC system is showing signs of premature wear in a tuned vehicle.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Misfire detection threshold map (mrwZUE_KF)">
    <Title>Misfire Detection Sensitivity (mrwZUE_KF)</Title>
    <Description>This map defines the thresholds for engine speed 'roughness' used to detect misfires. The ECU monitors the acceleration of the crankshaft after each firing event; if the acceleration is below these thresholds, the ECU flags a misfire. This is critical for EOBD compliance and engine protection.</Description>
    <UseCase>Diagnostic monitoring of combustion quality.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Do not modify. Lowering these thresholds will make the ECU blind to misfires, potentially leading to engine damage. Raising them may cause 'false positive' misfire codes, especially if a lightened flywheel is installed.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Fuel cooling control map (kuwKK_KF)">
    <Title>Fuel Cooling Pump Control (kuwKK_KF)</Title>
    <Description>Controls the activation and duty cycle of the fuel cooling system. PD engines return very hot fuel to the tank; this map ensures the fuel is cooled sufficiently to protect the fuel tank structure and maintain the lubricity of the diesel fuel for the high-pressure pump.</Description>
    <UseCase>Thermal management of the fuel system during high-load or high-ambient temperature operation.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Usually left stock. If you are running very high injection pressures or large nozzles that generate more heat, you may want to trigger the cooling pump earlier to keep fuel temperatures stable.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Electric fuel pump control (mrwEKP_KL)">
    <Title>Electric Lift Pump Control (mrwEKP_KL)</Title>
    <Description>This characteristic line manages the operation of the electric fuel lift pump located in the fuel tank. It ensures that the tandem pump on the cylinder head is always supplied with a steady flow of fuel, particularly during the start phase and under high engine load.</Description>
    <UseCase>Ensuring fuel supply reliability across the RPM and load range.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Usually left stock. If you have upgraded to a high-flow lift pump, this map may need adjustment to ensure the pump is not over-driven or causing excessive pressure in the return lines.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Tank shut-off valve control (mrwTAV_KL)">
    <Title>Tank Shut-off Valve (TAV) Logic (mrwTAV_KL)</Title>
    <Description>Defines the logic for the safety shut-off valve in the fuel tank. This valve is designed to immediately cut the fuel supply in the event of a detected crash (via the airbag signal) or a major system failure, preventing fuel from feeding a fire.</Description>
    <UseCase>Safety-critical fuel system isolation.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Do not modify. This is a primary safety feature of the vehicle. Disabling or delaying this valve can have life-threatening consequences in the event of an accident.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Gear-dependent torque limiters (mrwM_EBGxKL)">
    <Title>Gear-Dependent Torque/Quantity Limits (mrwM_EBGxKL)</Title>
    <Description>A series of characteristic lines (one for each gear) that define the maximum allowable torque or injection quantity. These are primarily used to protect the transmission and drivetrain components from excessive stress, particularly in lower gears where the torque multiplication is highest.</Description>
    <UseCase>Limiting torque in 1st and 2nd gear to prevent gearbox failure or excessive wheel spin.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>When increasing power, these limits must be raised proportionally. However, be cautious with 1st and 2nd gear limits to avoid stripping gears or damaging the differential.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="CVT-specific torque limit (mrwM_ECVTKL)">
    <Title>CVT Transmission Torque Limit (mrwM_ECVTKL)</Title>
    <Description>This characteristic line is specific to vehicles equipped with a Continuously Variable Transmission (CVT). It defines the maximum engine torque allowed to ensure the CVT belt does not slip and the variator pulleys are not overloaded.</Description>
    <UseCase>Drivetrain protection for CVT-equipped VAG models (e.g., early Multitronic systems).</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Exercise extreme caution. CVT transmissions are very sensitive to torque increases. Exceeding the factory limits often leads to rapid belt wear or total transmission failure.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Automated manual transmission limit (mrwM_EASGKL)">
    <Title>ASG/Automated Manual Torque Limit (mrwM_EASGKL)</Title>
    <Description>Defines the torque limits for Automated Manual Transmissions (ASG). This map is used by the ECU to coordinate torque reduction during automated gear shifts, ensuring smooth clutch transitions and protecting the internal shift actuators.</Description>
    <UseCase>Calibration of shift comfort and speed for ASG-equipped vehicles.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>If shifts feel 'jerky' after a tune, this map may need adjustment to allow for a smoother torque ramp-down and ramp-up during the shift phase.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="General transmission protection limit (mrwM_EGETKL)">
    <Title>TCU Requested Torque Limit (mrwM_EGETKL)</Title>
    <Description>A global torque limit requested by the Transmission Control Unit (TCU) via the CAN bus. This map defines how the ECU should respond to these external requests, typically used during gear changes or when the TCU detects a transmission over-temperature condition.</Description>
    <UseCase>Integration between the Engine ECU and Transmission ECU for drivetrain longevity.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Do not disable. This is the primary communication channel for the transmission to protect itself. If the TCU requests a limit, there is usually a valid mechanical reason.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="MAP/MAF switch (cowBEG_BOO/cowBEG_P_L)">
    <Title>MAP/MAF Configuration Switch (cowBEG_P_L)</Title>
    <Description>This configuration switch (Bosch mnemonic cowBEG_P_L or cowBEG_BOO) determines the primary input source for the smoke limiter logic. It allows the ECU to toggle between using the Mass Air Flow (MAF) sensor or the Manifold Absolute Pressure (MAP) sensor to calculate the maximum permissible fuel injection quantity. This is a fundamental switch in Bosch EDC15P systems for selecting the 'Rauchbegrenzung' strategy.</Description>
    <UseCase>Used to enable 'MAF-less' tuning. By setting this switch to 1 (MAP-based), the tuner can bypass a faulty or restrictive MAF sensor and rely entirely on the boost pressure sensor for smoke control.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>When switching to MAP-based limiting, ensure that the 'IQ by MAP limiter' map is correctly calibrated for the engine's volumetric efficiency. Setting this switch without a calibrated MAP-based smoke map will result in poor drivability or excessive smoke.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="VCDS Diagnostic IQ Limit (1-10)">
    <Title>Diagnostic IQ Display Limit</Title>
    <Description>This value defines the maximum injection quantity (IQ) that can be reported through the diagnostic interface (K-Line/VCDS). It is a display-only limit and does not affect the actual engine performance or the internal 'Mengenberechnung' logic.</Description>
    <UseCase>Essential for high-power builds where the requested IQ exceeds the factory display limit (typically 70mg). Increasing this allows for accurate data logging during dyno runs or road testing.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Set this value slightly higher than the maximum value in your Torque Limiter map to ensure that logs show the true injected quantity without clipping.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Fuel tank inlet temp overheat protection (mrwBTT_KF)">
    <Title>Fuel Tank Inlet Overheat Protection (mrwBTT_KF)</Title>
    <Description>This safety map monitors the temperature of the fuel returning to the tank (mrwBTT). If the fuel becomes too hot, the ECU reduces the maximum allowable injection quantity to protect the fuel tank structure and the tandem pump from thermal stress. High fuel temperatures also reduce the lubricity of diesel, increasing wear on PD injectors.</Description>
    <UseCase>Protects the fuel system hardware during extreme operating conditions or in the event of a failing fuel cooler.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Generally should be left stock. If power loss occurs due to fuel temperature, investigate the efficiency of the fuel cooling system rather than raising these safety limits.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Desired speed message to transmission (mrwBCV_KF)">
    <Title>Transmission Desired Speed Message (mrwBCV_KF)</Title>
    <Description>This map calculates the desired engine speed value that is communicated to the Automatic Transmission Control Unit (TCU) via the CAN bus. It helps the TCU determine optimal shift points based on current engine load and driver request.</Description>
    <UseCase>Calibration of shift behavior for vehicles equipped with AG4 or early 5-speed Tiptronic transmissions.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Only modify if the transmission shift points feel mismatched to the new power band after engine tuning. Coordinate changes with TCU remapping if possible.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Injected Fuel Volume Correction at 100°C (mrwKTB_KF)">
    <Title>Fuel Volume Correction at 100°C (mrwKTB_KF)</Title>
    <Description>This map (mrwKTB_KF) applies a correction factor to the injected quantity when the fuel temperature reaches high levels (referenced at 100°C). It accounts for the change in fuel density and viscosity, ensuring that the actual mass of fuel delivered remains consistent with the ECU's torque model.</Description>
    <UseCase>Ensures fueling accuracy and engine protection during high-thermal load operation.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Usually left stock. In extreme performance applications with very high injection pressures, small adjustments may be needed to maintain perfect AFR as the fuel heats up.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Calculation of specific consumption (mrwKFVB_KF)">
    <Title>Specific Fuel Consumption Calculation (mrwKFVB_KF)</Title>
    <Description>This map is used by the ECU to calculate the instantaneous fuel consumption. The result is typically sent via CAN to the instrument cluster (Kombiinstrument) for display on the FIS/MFA trip computer.</Description>
    <UseCase>Used to calibrate the accuracy of the dashboard fuel consumption display.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>If the dashboard reports significantly different fuel consumption than actual (measured at the pump) after installing larger injectors, this map can be adjusted to 're-scale' the display.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="BIP SOI Correction Map (zmwBPKorKF)">
    <Title>BIP-Based SOI Correction (zmwBPKorKF)</Title>
    <Description>This map applies a correction to the Start of Injection (SOI) based on the detected BIP (Begin of Injection Period) deviation. It ensures that the actual start of combustion remains synchronized with the crankshaft angle even if the injector solenoid response time varies due to temperature or wear.</Description>
    <UseCase>Fine-tuning injection timing accuracy for PD (Pumpe Düse) engines.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Do not modify without high-speed oscilloscope data or specialized BIP logging. Incorrect values will lead to timing jitter and increased mechanical stress on the engine.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Start of delivery turn swell map (fnwUMDR_KF / fnwUMRMEKF)">
    <Title>Start of Delivery Turn Swell (fnwUMDR_KF)</Title>
    <Description>This map compensates for the mechanical 'swell' or delay in the high-pressure pump system during the initial cranking phase. It ensures that the first injection events occur at the correct pressure and timing to facilitate a rapid start.</Description>
    <UseCase>Improving engine start-up speed and reliability.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Usually left stock. If the engine is slow to fire despite a healthy starter and battery, small adjustments here can help optimize the initial delivery.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Start of delivery ATM pressure correction (fnwSWSN_KF)">
    <Title>SOI Cranking Altitude Correction (fnwSWSN_KF)</Title>
    <Description>Adjusts the Start of Injection (SOI) during the cranking phase based on the ambient atmospheric pressure. Thinner air at high altitudes requires different timing to ensure reliable ignition during a cold start.</Description>
    <UseCase>Ensures reliable starting in mountainous regions.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Usually left stock. If the engine struggles to start only at high altitudes, small timing advances can be calibrated here.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Acceleration limitation map (mrwBdn_KF)">
    <Title>Acceleration Gradient Limit (mrwBdn_KF)</Title>
    <Description>This map defines the maximum permissible rate of change for engine speed (dn/dt). It acts as a dynamic limiter that prevents the engine from accelerating too rapidly in a way that would cause drivetrain 'bucking' or exceed the physical limits of the transmission components. Bosch refers to this as the 'Beschleunigungsbegrenzung'.</Description>
    <UseCase>Used to smooth out the power delivery in low gears or to protect fragile drivetrain components from sudden torque spikes.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Increasing these values will make the engine feel more 'raw' and responsive, but at the cost of increased drivetrain stress. Decrease these values if the car feels jerky during rapid acceleration.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Generator load torque loss map (mrwDFMD_KF)">
    <Title>Alternator Torque Compensation (mrwDFMD_KF)</Title>
    <Description>Estimates the mechanical torque (in Nm) required to drive the alternator based on the electrical load (DF signal) and engine speed. The ECU uses this value to proactively adjust the injection quantity, ensuring that the idle speed remains stable when heavy electrical consumers (like seat heaters or window defrosters) are switched on.</Description>
    <UseCase>Maintains idle refinement and prevents the engine from 'dipping' or stumbling under electrical load.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Generally should not be touched. If you have installed a significantly higher-output alternator, this map may need adjustment to maintain perfect idle stability.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="ARD Ramp rate load change - positive (mrwFPRA_KF)">
    <Title>ARD Positive Ramp Rate (mrwFPRA_KF)</Title>
    <Description>The Active Anti-Jerk Filter (ARD) uses this map to control the maximum rate of increase for the injected quantity during rapid throttle applications. It smooths out the transition to prevent mechanical oscillations in the drivetrain, known as 'bucking' or 'jerking'. Bosch refers to this as the 'Führungsformer'.</Description>
    <UseCase>Adjusted to sharpen the engine's response to throttle inputs. Higher values allow for faster torque build-up.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Increase values carefully to improve throttle 'snap'. If increased too much, the car may become difficult to drive smoothly in low gears, as every small pedal movement will cause a sharp surge in torque.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="ARD Ramp rate load change - negative (mrwFNRA_KF)">
    <Title>ARD Negative Ramp Rate (mrwFNRA_KF)</Title>
    <Description>This map controls the rate at which fuel is reduced when the driver lifts off the accelerator. Similar to the positive ramp, it prevents the engine from 'dropping' too quickly, which can cause uncomfortable drivetrain lash and vibrations.</Description>
    <UseCase>Modified to achieve a more natural engine braking feel or to prevent 'clunking' during rapid lift-off.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Decrease values to allow for faster engine braking. If the lift-off feels too abrupt or causes drivetrain noise, increase the values to slow down the fuel reduction ramp.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Glow plugs glow control map (gswTV4_KF)">
    <Title>Glow Plug PWM Control (gswTV4_KF)</Title>
    <Description>This map controls the pulse-width modulation (PWM) duty cycle sent to the glow plugs. It determines the intensity and duration of the heating phase based on the engine coolant temperature. Proper glow plug operation is essential for reducing cranking time and emissions during a cold start.</Description>
    <UseCase>Critical for reliable starting in extreme cold conditions.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>If the vehicle struggles to start in very cold weather despite healthy glow plugs, the duty cycle or duration can be increased. Avoid excessive heating as it will significantly shorten the lifespan of the glow plugs.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Cooling fan demand map (kuwANF_KF)">
    <Title>Cooling Fan Demand (kuwANF_KF)</Title>
    <Description>This map translates the ECU's internal cooling request (based on coolant, oil, and AC pressures) into a specific fan speed or duty cycle. It is the primary interface between the thermal management logic and the fan hardware.</Description>
    <UseCase>Modified to trigger cooling fans earlier or at higher speeds in hot climates or for track-focused vehicles.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Lowering the temperature thresholds can help keep the engine in its optimal thermal window during aggressive driving. Ensure the electrical system can handle the increased load if fans are set to run at 100% duty cycle frequently.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Water critical temperature basic map (kuwWTFkrKF)">
    <Title>Critical Coolant Temperature (kuwWTFkrKF)</Title>
    <Description>Defines the 'critical' temperature limits for the engine coolant based on engine speed and load. When the coolant temperature exceeds these thresholds, the ECU enters an emergency cooling mode, triggering maximum fan speed and potentially reducing fuel injection (IQ) to prevent catastrophic overheating.</Description>
    <UseCase>Primary safety monitoring for the engine's thermal state.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Do not increase these values. These are hard safety limits designed to protect the engine block and head from warping or cracking due to extreme heat.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Altitude dependent speed correction (mrwBATM_KF)">
    <Title>Altitude Speed Correction (mrwBATM_KF)</Title>
    <Description>This map adjusts the engine speed limits or targets based on the current atmospheric pressure. Its primary purpose is to protect the turbocharger from over-speeding at high altitudes, where the air is thinner and the turbine must spin faster to maintain boost.</Description>
    <UseCase>Ensures turbocharger longevity during mountain driving or in high-altitude regions.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Do not increase these values unless you have verified the turbocharger's maximum safe RPM at low air densities. Reducing these values can provide an extra safety margin for high-boost setups.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Target idle speed map (mrwWTAD_KF)">
    <Title>Target Idle Speed (mrwWTAD_KF)</Title>
    <Description>Sets the steady-state target idle speed (RPM) based on engine coolant temperature. A higher idle at low temperatures helps the engine warm up faster and ensures stable oil pressure.</Description>
    <UseCase>Adjusted to improve cold-start refinement or to raise the idle speed if a lightened flywheel causes vibration.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Ensure the transition from cold to warm idle is smooth. Setting the idle too high when warm will increase fuel consumption and noise.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Torq limiter - Min map (mrwADB_KF)">
    <Title>Minimum Torque Limiter (mrwADB_KF)</Title>
    <Description>This map defines the absolute minimum torque or injection quantity allowed. It acts as a 'floor' for the torque calculation chain, ensuring that the engine always maintains enough fueling to sustain operation and drive auxiliary components like the alternator and AC compressor.</Description>
    <UseCase>Ensures engine stability and prevents stalling under heavy auxiliary load.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Usually left stock. Only modify if the engine stalls when heavy loads are applied at idle despite a healthy idle controller.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Inverse driver wish">
    <Title>Inverse Driver Wish (mroM_EFAH)</Title>
    <Description>The Inverse Driver Wish map is the mathematical reciprocal of the primary Driver Wish map. It translates a requested torque or Injected Quantity (IQ) back into a theoretical accelerator pedal percentage. This is used by the ECU for internal monitoring and plausibility checks, ensuring that the requested load matches the driver's physical input.</Description>
    <UseCase>Used by the ECU to verify that the torque calculation chain has not been corrupted or subjected to an implausible external intervention.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>If you have significantly modified the Driver Wish map, you should update the Inverse Driver Wish map to match. Failure to do so can lead to 'limp mode' or 'implausible signal' errors because the ECU's internal cross-check will fail.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="SOI limiter (temperature)">
    <Title>SOI Temperature Limiter (fnwSWGK_KL)</Title>
    <Description>This map limits the maximum Start of Injection (SOI) advance based on engine coolant temperature. It acts as a thermal safety ceiling to prevent excessive cylinder pressures when the engine is cold or dangerously hot. Bosch logic uses this to protect the head gasket and pistons from the high peak pressures associated with aggressive timing.</Description>
    <UseCase>Protects the engine from mechanical damage due to excessive timing advance during the warm-up phase.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>When advancing SOI for performance, ensure this limiter is also raised to allow your new timing targets to be reached. However, always maintain a safe margin to prevent 'diesel knock' on a cold engine.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="AG4 Transmission downshift map (mrwM_ER_KF)">
    <Title>AG4 Transmission Downshift Torque Map</Title>
    <Description>This map defines the torque limits or characteristics communicated to the AG4 automatic transmission during a downshift. It ensures that the engine speed is synchronized correctly with the lower gear ratio to provide a smooth transition without drivetrain shock.</Description>
    <UseCase>Critical for maintaining shift quality in automatic vehicles after a power increase.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>If the transmission 'thumps' or shifts harshly during downshifts after tuning, these values may need adjustment to match the engine's new torque response.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Radiator fan-caster correction map 2 (kuwNLKORK2)">
    <Title>Radiator Fan After-Run Correction 2 (kuwNLKORK2)</Title>
    <Description>A secondary correction map for the radiator fan after-run logic. It fine-tunes the fan speed or duration based on additional environmental factors such as refrigerant pressure or intake air temperature, ensuring the engine bay is cooled effectively after shutdown.</Description>
    <UseCase>Refining the thermal management strategy for high-performance or heavy-duty applications.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Usually left stock. Can be increased in track-focused builds to combat heat soak more aggressively.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Hydraulic fan speed normalization (kuwHyLFTKF)">
    <Title>Hydraulic Fan Speed Normalization (kuwHyLFTKF)</Title>
    <Description>This map normalizes the speed request for hydraulic cooling fans. Since hydraulic fans are driven by an engine-mounted pump, their potential speed varies with engine RPM. This map ensures that the actual fan speed remains consistent with the ECU's cooling request regardless of engine speed.</Description>
    <UseCase>Calibration for vehicles equipped with hydraulic cooling systems.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Usually left stock. If cooling performance is inconsistent across the RPM range, this map may need adjustment to account for pump efficiency.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Water temperature basic setpoint (kuwSOLL1KF)">
    <Title>Coolant Temperature Setpoint (kuwSOLL1KF)</Title>
    <Description>This map defines the base target temperature for the engine coolant. The ECU uses this value to manage the thermostat and cooling fans, attempting to keep the engine within its optimal thermal efficiency window.</Description>
    <UseCase>Used to lower the engine's operating temperature for performance or track use.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Lowering the setpoint can help prevent heat soak during aggressive driving, but setting it too low will reduce fuel efficiency and increase engine wear.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Oil temperature overheat protection (mrwBOEL_KF)">
    <Title>Oil Temperature Overheat Protection (mrwBOEL_KF)</Title>
    <Description>This map limits the injected quantity based on engine oil temperature. As oil temperature rises beyond safe operating limits, the ECU reduces engine load to prevent thermal runaway and mechanical failure. It is a critical part of the Bosch 'Motorschutz' strategy.</Description>
    <UseCase>Prevents catastrophic engine damage if the cooling system is overwhelmed.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Do not modify this map unless you have installed significantly upgraded oil cooling and are monitoring temperatures with high-precision sensors.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="CVT Transmission drag torque limitation (mrwSchmxKF)">
    <Title>CVT Drag Torque Limit (mrwSchmxKF)</Title>
    <Description>This map limits the engine's drag torque (negative torque) during deceleration in vehicles equipped with a CVT. It protects the CVT belt and pulleys from the high mechanical stresses caused by rapid changes in engine speed.</Description>
    <UseCase>Critical for maintaining CVT longevity in tuned vehicles.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Generally should be left stock. If the CVT is slipping during deceleration after a power increase, these limits may need to be tightened.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Air mass calculation air temp/pressure (arwLMBKOKF)">
    <Title>Air Mass Environmental Correction (arwLMBKOKF)</Title>
    <Description>Applies a correction factor to the air mass calculation based on intake air temperature and atmospheric pressure. This ensures that the ECU's internal model of air density remains accurate, which is critical for precise smoke limiting and EGR control.</Description>
    <UseCase>Maintaining fueling accuracy across different altitudes and weather conditions.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Usually left stock. For extreme high-boost applications where intake temperatures are significantly higher than factory, this map may need calibration.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Injection dynamic advance map">
    <Title>Dynamic Injection Advance (fnwSWDY_KF)</Title>
    <Description>This map defines the additional injection advance (SOI) applied during rapid load changes or transients. It ensures that the combustion timing reacts quickly enough to support sudden increases in torque request, preventing 'timing lag' that could lead to poor combustion or smoke during acceleration.</Description>
    <UseCase>Used to sharpen the engine's response during rapid throttle applications.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Usually left stock. If the engine feels 'flat' during the initial phase of acceleration despite aggressive base SOI maps, small increases here can improve the 'snap' of the engine.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="MAF airmass correction by temperature">
    <Title>MAF Temperature Correction (mroM_LK)</Title>
    <Description>This map corrects the air mass reading from the MAF sensor based on the intake air temperature. Since the density of air changes with temperature, this correction is vital for the ECU to accurately determine the actual oxygen content available for combustion.</Description>
    <UseCase>Ensures consistent smoke limiting and fueling across varying weather conditions.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Only modify if you have changed the intake plumbing or intercooler in a way that significantly alters the temperature-density relationship at the MAF sensor.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Water temp full load increase (mrwBPL_KF)">
    <Title>Full Load IQ Increase - Coolant Temp (mrwBPL_KF)</Title>
    <Description>This map allows for an increase in the maximum injected quantity (IQ) at full load based on the engine coolant temperature. It is often used to provide extra power during the warm-up phase or to compensate for thermal conditions where the engine can safely handle more fuel.</Description>
    <UseCase>Fine-tuning the full-load performance across the engine's thermal operating range.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Use with caution. Increasing full-load IQ when the engine is cold can lead to excessive mechanical stress, while doing so when hot can lead to overheating.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="EGR control small-quantity on (arwREG1KL)">
    <Title>EGR Small-Quantity Activation (arwREG1KL)</Title>
    <Description>This characteristic line defines the injection quantity threshold where the EGR system becomes active. Below this threshold (e.g., during very light load or idle), the ECU enables the EGR control loop to reduce NOx emissions.</Description>
    <UseCase>Calibration of the EGR activation window.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>If you want the EGR to stay off during light cruising, you can lower these thresholds. This is often part of a partial EGR delete strategy.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Smooth-running controller LRR limiting (mrwLRR_BGR)">
    <Title>Smooth Running Controller Limit (mrwLRR_BGR)</Title>
    <Description>This characteristic line defines the maximum correction (in mg/stroke) that the Smooth Running Controller (LRR) is allowed to apply to any individual cylinder. It prevents the cylinder balancing logic from making extreme adjustments that could mask a genuine mechanical failure.</Description>
    <UseCase>Safety limit for the cylinder balancing system.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Usually left stock. If you have installed very large injectors with high flow variance, you may need to increase this limit to allow the ECU to balance the idle effectively.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="AC Compressor water temp switch-off (klwWTab_KL)">
    <Title>AC Switch-Off - Coolant Temp (klwWTab_KL)</Title>
    <Description>This characteristic line defines the coolant temperature threshold above which the ECU automatically deactivates the air conditioning compressor. This is a protective measure to reduce engine load and heat production when the cooling system is near its limit.</Description>
    <UseCase>Engine protection during extreme overheating conditions.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Do not increase this threshold. It is a vital safety feature that prevents the engine from overheating further when the cooling system is already struggling.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Idle RPM">
    <Title>Idle Speed Setpoint (mroN_LL)</Title>
    <Description>This characteristic defines the base target idle speed for the engine. It is the primary setpoint for the idle speed controller (LLR) when the engine is at operating temperature and no auxiliary loads are active.</Description>
    <UseCase>Used to raise the idle speed to combat vibrations from a lightened flywheel or to improve oil pressure at idle in high-performance builds.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Small increases (e.g., from 903 to 950 RPM) are common. Avoid setting it too high as it increases fuel consumption and noise at a standstill.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="VCDS Diagnostic MAF Limit (1-2)">
    <Title>Diagnostic MAF Display Limit</Title>
    <Description>Defines the maximum air mass value (mg/stroke) that can be displayed via diagnostic protocols. This is a scaling value for the diagnostic output and does not affect the actual engine control logic.</Description>
    <UseCase>Increased when tuning for high boost levels where actual air mass exceeds the factory display range.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Set to match the maximum expected air mass from your MAF sensor linearization.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="VCDS Diagnostic MAP Limit (1-3)">
    <Title>Diagnostic MAP Display Limit</Title>
    <Description>Defines the maximum boost pressure (mbar) that can be displayed via VCDS. This is a diagnostic scaling factor.</Description>
    <UseCase>Modified when using 4-bar MAP sensors to ensure the diagnostic logs show the full pressure range.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Set to 4000mbar if using a 4-bar sensor.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Left Foot Brake Switch">
    <Title>Left Foot Braking Switch (cowBRE_LFB)</Title>
    <Description>A configuration switch that enables or disables the torque reduction logic when the brake and accelerator pedals are pressed simultaneously. By default, Bosch logic cuts fuel if the brake is applied while the throttle is open.</Description>
    <UseCase>Used in performance driving to allow 'left foot braking' without the ECU cutting power.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Set to 0 to disable the safety cut-off for track use.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="BIP Basic characteristic line">
    <Title>BIP Basic Characteristic (zmwBPGndKL)</Title>
    <Description>The fundamental calibration line for the Begin of Injection Period (BIP). It describes the expected electrical response time of the PD injector solenoid under standard conditions.</Description>
    <UseCase>Calibration for specific injector hardware.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Do not modify unless changing to a different injector type.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="BIP temperature correction">
    <Title>BIP Temperature Correction (zmwBPKorKL)</Title>
    <Description>Corrects the expected BIP signal based on fuel temperature. As fuel temperature changes, the solenoid's electrical resistance and the fuel's viscosity alter the needle's response time.</Description>
    <UseCase>Ensures timing accuracy across the engine's thermal range.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Leave stock unless you have precise injector test-bench data.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Grid table for speed input dzmNmit (fnwDZstzv)">
    <Title>SOI Speed Axis Definition (fnwDZstzv)</Title>
    <Description>This is a grid table (axis) defining the engine speed (RPM) breakpoints for the Start of Injection (SOI) maps. It determines the resolution of the timing maps across the RPM range.</Description>
    <UseCase>Used to re-scale the SOI maps for higher RPM ranges (e.g., extending the axis to 5500+ RPM).</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Ensure that the corresponding SOI maps are also updated to match the new axis breakpoints.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Grid table for duration quantity fnoM_E (fnwMEstzv)">
    <Title>Duration Quantity Axis Definition (fnwMEstzv)</Title>
    <Description>Defines the Injected Quantity (IQ) breakpoints for the Injector Duration maps. It sets the load-axis resolution for fueling calibration.</Description>
    <UseCase>Modified when tuning for very high IQ (e.g., >70mg) to ensure the duration maps have enough resolution at the top end.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Coordinate changes with the Duration maps to maintain fueling accuracy.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Grid table for water temperature fnmWTF (fnwWTstzv)">
    <Title>Coolant Temp Axis Definition (fnwWTstzv)</Title>
    <Description>Defines the temperature breakpoints for SOI and other temperature-dependent maps.</Description>
    <UseCase>Used to change the resolution of thermal compensation logic.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Usually left stock.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Grid table for corrected airmass mroM_LK (mrwLKstzv)">
    <Title>Airmass Axis Definition (mrwLKstzv)</Title>
    <Description>Defines the air mass (mg/stroke) breakpoints for the Smoke Limiter and other MAF-dependent maps.</Description>
    <UseCase>Modified when upgrading to larger turbos that flow significantly more air than the factory axis supports.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Ensure the Smoke Limiter map is re-calibrated to match the new axis values.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Measurement Blocks 190-199 values">
    <Title>Diagnostic Measurement Block Values</Title>
    <Description>This map defines the data structure and scaling for the extended measurement blocks (190-199) used in VAG diagnostic protocols. It determines which internal RAM variables are reported to the scan tool.</Description>
    <UseCase>Used by developers to expose custom internal variables for logging.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Do not modify unless you are implementing custom ECU patches.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Parallel control engine temp correction (arwSTTWKF)">
    <Title>EGR Parallel Control - Temp Correction (arwSTTWKF)</Title>
    <Description>This map adjusts the EGR duty cycle based on engine temperature when the system is operating in 'parallel control' mode. It ensures emissions compliance during the warm-up phase.</Description>
    <UseCase>Fine-tuning EGR behavior during engine warm-up.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Set to values that close the EGR if a cleaner intake is desired during warm-up.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Engine Oil soot level map (siwOEL_rKF)">
    <Title>Oil Soot Loading Model (siwOEL_rKF)</Title>
    <Description>Part of the Bosch Flexible Service Interval (WIV) logic. This map estimates the soot accumulation in the engine oil based on engine load and speed. The ECU uses this to calculate when an oil change is required.</Description>
    <UseCase>Internal model for service interval calculation.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Leave stock. The ECU will naturally shorten intervals if the engine is run at higher loads.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="EGR temperature map">
    <Title>EGR Temperature Model</Title>
    <Description>This map estimates the temperature of the recirculated exhaust gas. It is used to protect the intake manifold from melting and to calculate the final charge temperature for combustion modeling.</Description>
    <UseCase>Component protection and combustion accuracy.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Usually left stock.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Cooler run-on characteristic - Electric (kuwNlEL_KF)">
    <Title>Electric Fan Run-On (kuwNlEL_KF)</Title>
    <Description>Defines the duration and speed of the electric cooling fans after the engine is turned off, based on the last known coolant temperature.</Description>
    <UseCase>Managing heat soak after high-load operation.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Increase values for track cars to ensure the engine bay cools down effectively after a session.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Weighting torque correction map (mrwKFTkorr)">
    <Title>Torque Weighting Correction (mrwKFTkorr)</Title>
    <Description>A fine-tuning map that applies a weighting factor to the final torque calculation. It accounts for minor variations in engine efficiency across different operating points.</Description>
    <UseCase>Refining the accuracy of the ECU's torque model.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Usually left stock.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="EGR Pressure correction map (arw2LM_KF)">
    <Title>EGR Pressure Correction (arw2LM_KF)</Title>
    <Description>Corrects the EGR flow calculation based on the pressure differential across the EGR valve. This ensures that the requested EGR mass is delivered accurately regardless of boost or exhaust backpressure.</Description>
    <UseCase>Calibration of EGR accuracy.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Leave stock.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="EGR Engine temp correction - Target (arwTWVEKF)">
    <Title>EGR Target Temp Correction (arwTWVEKF)</Title>
    <Description>Adjusts the EGR setpoint (target air mass) based on engine coolant temperature. It is used to increase EGR rates when the engine is cold to speed up the warm-up process.</Description>
    <UseCase>Emissions and warm-up management.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Modify if you want to reduce EGR during the warm-up phase.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="EGR Basic-Setpoint map (VP44) (arwTWVEKF)">
    <Title>EGR Base Setpoint - VP44 (arwTWVEKF)</Title>
    <Description>The primary EGR setpoint map for engines equipped with the Bosch VP44 pump. It defines the desired air mass for a given speed and load.</Description>
    <UseCase>EGR tuning for V6 TDI engines (e.g., AFB, AKN).</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Set to maximum air mass values to disable EGR.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Ambient temperature sensor linearization">
    <Title>Ambient Temp Sensor Linearization (anwUTF_KL)</Title>
    <Description>Scales the raw signal from the outside air temperature sensor. This value is used for various environmental corrections and display purposes.</Description>
    <UseCase>Calibration for custom sensor locations or types.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Leave stock.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Advanced thrust characteristic map (mrwSCHUPKL)">
    <Title>Thrust/Overrun Characteristic (mrwSCHUPKL)</Title>
    <Description>This map defines the engine's behavior during 'thrust' or overrun (deceleration). It manages the transition from fueled operation to zero-fueling, influencing engine braking feel and smoothness.</Description>
    <UseCase>Refining the transition into overrun.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Adjust if the engine braking feels too abrupt or if there is a 'jerk' when lifting off the throttle.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Permissible heating time map (mrwWTF_KL)">
    <Title>Max Heating Duration (mrwWTF_KL)</Title>
    <Description>Defines the maximum allowed time for the glow plugs or auxiliary heaters to remain active, based on coolant temperature. It is a safety limit to prevent heater burnout.</Description>
    <UseCase>Protection of the heating elements.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Do not increase beyond the hardware's rated limits.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Smoke/boost pressure compensation (mrwKFPkorr)">
    <Title>Smoke/Boost Compensation (mrwKFPkorr)</Title>
    <Description>A correction line that adjusts the smoke limiter's behavior based on rapid changes in boost pressure. It helps the ECU anticipate air mass changes during turbo spool-up.</Description>
    <UseCase>Reducing 'spool-up smoke' during rapid acceleration.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Fine-tune this to achieve a clean transition from vacuum to full boost.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Water heat dissipation map (kmw_ThHzKL)">
    <Title>Coolant Heat Dissipation (kmw_ThHzKL)</Title>
    <Description>This map models the rate at which the engine dissipates heat to the environment. It is used by the thermal management logic to predict temperature changes and control the fans/thermostat proactively.</Description>
    <UseCase>Internal thermal modeling.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Leave stock.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="ASG-ECO Mode torque limiter (mrwBDB2_KL)">
    <Title>ASG ECO Torque Limiter (mrwBDB2_KL)</Title>
    <Description>A specific torque limiter used when the vehicle is in 'ECO' mode (common in Lupo 3L or Audi A2 1.2 TDI). It restricts the engine's output to maximize fuel economy.</Description>
    <UseCase>ECO mode tuning.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Increase these values if more power is desired while still in ECO mode.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Starting torque quantity characterization (mrwANFAHKL)">
    <Title>Starting Torque Quantity (mrwANFAHKL)</Title>
    <Description>Defines the initial torque or fuel quantity delivered at the very first moment of cranking. It ensures the engine has enough 'kick' to begin rotating.</Description>
    <UseCase>Improving initial fire-up reliability.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Small increases can help engines that are 'lazy' to start.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Pre-glow map">
    <Title>Pre-Glow Duration (gswGS_t1KL)</Title>
    <Description>Defines the duration of the pre-heating phase for the glow plugs before the engine is cranked. The time is heavily dependent on coolant temperature.</Description>
    <UseCase>Improving cold start reliability.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Increase for better starting in extremely cold climates.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Boost control - maximum positive deviation (ldwRMXpRKL)">
    <Title>Max Positive Boost Deviation (ldwRMXpRKL)</Title>
    <Description>Defines the maximum allowed 'overshoot' (actual boost > target boost) before the ECU triggers a diagnostic fault or enters limp mode.</Description>
    <UseCase>Preventing nuisance limp mode on aggressive setups.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Increase slightly if your turbo spools very fast and causes a brief, harmless spike.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Boost control - cold start shutdown (ldwKSTWKL)">
    <Title>Cold Start Boost Deactivation (ldwKSTWKL)</Title>
    <Description>This characteristic line defines the temperature threshold below which the boost control system is deactivated or restricted. This protects the cold turbocharger from high loads until the oil has reached a safe operating temperature.</Description>
    <UseCase>Turbocharger protection during warm-up.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Do not disable. It is vital for the longevity of the turbo bearings.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Cooling water heating characteristic (khwKHTL_KL)">
    <Title>Auxiliary Heater Characteristic (khwKHTL_KL)</Title>
    <Description>Manages the activation of the electric auxiliary coolant heaters (glow plugs in the water flange). These heaters help the cabin reach a comfortable temperature faster in cold weather.</Description>
    <UseCase>Cold weather comfort management.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Usually left stock.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Boost pressure control OFF threshold (ldwREG0WKL)">
    <Title>Boost Control Deactivation (ldwREG0WKL)</Title>
    <Description>Defines the engine speed or load threshold where the closed-loop boost control is deactivated (e.g., during overrun or very low load).</Description>
    <UseCase>Ensuring stable turbo behavior at low loads.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Leave stock.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Delay - EGR start time after startup (anwANSTWKL)">
    <Title>EGR Startup Delay (anwANSTWKL)</Title>
    <Description>Defines a delay period after the engine starts before the EGR system is allowed to activate. This ensures the engine has stabilized its idle before recirculating exhaust gas.</Description>
    <UseCase>Improving idle stability immediately after start.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Increase the delay to keep the intake cleaner during the first few minutes of operation.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Map - Boost intake manifold vacuum cancellation (mrwLDFO_KL)">
    <Title>Intake Vacuum Cancellation (mrwLDFO_KL)</Title>
    <Description>Defines the pressure threshold for cancelling a detected intake vacuum condition. It is the hysteresis counterpart to the vacuum detection map.</Description>
    <UseCase>Diagnostic stability.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Do not modify.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="RME Sensor linearization map (anwRME_KL)">
    <Title>RME/Biodiesel Sensor Linearization (anwRME_KL)</Title>
    <Description>Scales the signal from the fuel quality sensor (RME sensor). This sensor detects the percentage of biodiesel in the fuel, allowing the ECU to adjust timing and duration for different fuel properties.</Description>
    <UseCase>Calibration for biodiesel compatibility.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Leave stock unless retrofitting a sensor.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="IQ by air intake temp">
    <Title>IQ Limit - Intake Air Temp (ldwTLUEKL)</Title>
    <Description>This characteristic line reduces the maximum injected quantity as intake air temperature (IAT) rises. It is a safety feature to prevent excessive Exhaust Gas Temperatures (EGT) and protect the engine from leaning out in hot weather.</Description>
    <UseCase>Engine protection in hot climates.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>If you have a very efficient intercooler, you may be able to relax these limits slightly, but always monitor EGTs.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Oil temperature correction line (kuwNLOELKL)">
    <Title>Fan Speed - Oil Temp Correction (kuwNLOELKL)</Title>
    <Description>Adjusts the cooling fan speed based on engine oil temperature. This ensures that the oil is kept within a safe thermal window even if the coolant temperature is stable.</Description>
    <UseCase>Thermal management of engine oil.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Increase fan speed at high oil temperatures for track use.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="EGR cooler bypass switch-off line (arwERGnAus)">
    <Title>EGR Cooler Bypass Deactivation (arwERGnAus)</Title>
    <Description>Defines the conditions under which the EGR cooler bypass valve is closed, forcing exhaust gas through the cooler. This is used to manage the temperature of the recirculated gas.</Description>
    <UseCase>EGR thermal management.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Leave stock.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="ARD shaper gradient bandwidth positive - pos offset (mrwFPoO_KL)">
    <Title>ARD Positive Shaper Offset (mrwFPoO_KL)</Title>
    <Description>Fine-tunes the sensitivity of the anti-jerk positive ramp. It defines the 'bandwidth' or tolerance for the load-shaping logic during acceleration.</Description>
    <UseCase>Refining anti-jerk response.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Usually left stock.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Ambient temperature water correction line (kmwWTkorKL)">
    <Title>Coolant Setpoint - Ambient Correction (kmwWTkorKL)</Title>
    <Description>Adjusts the target coolant temperature based on the outside air temperature. The ECU may request a higher temperature in cold weather to improve heater performance.</Description>
    <UseCase>Environmental thermal management.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Leave stock.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Boost shutdown freeze time curve (ldwVZAR_KL)">
    <Title>Boost Protection Delay (ldwVZAR_KL)</Title>
    <Description>Defines the delay time for boost-related safety interventions during rapid transients. It prevents the ECU from entering limp mode during very brief boost spikes.</Description>
    <UseCase>Nuisance limp mode prevention.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Increase slightly if gear changes trigger limp mode despite good N75 tuning.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Pedal position linearization map (mrwADR_KL)">
    <Title>Pedal Linearization (mrwADR_KL)</Title>
    <Description>Scales the raw voltage from the accelerator pedal sensor into a percentage (0-100%). It is the first step in the driver wish calculation.</Description>
    <UseCase>Calibration for different pedal hardware.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Do not modify unless the physical pedal has been changed.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="EGR- Engine temperature dependent drop map (arwUMDRpKL)">
    <Title>EGR Temp-Dependent Drop (arwUMDRpKL)</Title>
    <Description>Reduces the EGR rate as engine temperature rises to prevent excessive intake temperatures and maintain combustion efficiency.</Description>
    <UseCase>EGR thermal management.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Leave stock.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="IAT dependent - Boost correction (ldwTVTLKL)">
    <Title>Boost Correction - Intake Temp (ldwTVTLKL)</Title>
    <Description>Adjusts the target boost pressure based on intake air temperature. The ECU may reduce boost in very hot weather to protect the turbocharger and engine.</Description>
    <UseCase>Thermal protection.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Ensure this map is calibrated if running high boost levels that generate significant heat.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Digital/analog Temperature correction (anwUTF_KL)">
    <Title>Temp Sensor Signal Correction (anwUTF_KL)</Title>
    <Description>A correction line that accounts for the difference between digital and analog signal processing for temperature sensors, ensuring the ECU has a consistent temperature reading.</Description>
    <UseCase>Signal integrity.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Do not modify.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Speed dependent - Boost actuator lower limit (ldwGRminKL)">
    <Title>N75 Actuator Lower Limit (ldwGRminKL)</Title>
    <Description>Defines the minimum allowed duty cycle for the N75 solenoid. It prevents the VNT vanes from closing too much at high RPM, which would cause excessive backpressure.</Description>
    <UseCase>Turbocharger protection.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Ensure this is set high enough to prevent 'choking' the engine at high RPM.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Speed dependent - Quantity limit threshold (mrwBMVE_KL)">
    <Title>IQ Limit Threshold - Speed (mrwBMVE_KL)</Title>
    <Description>Defines the engine speed threshold for activating certain injection quantity limits, typically used for component protection or emissions control.</Description>
    <UseCase>Speed-based fueling restriction.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Leave stock.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="CAN relative cooling capacity curve (kuwTV_KL)">
    <Title>CAN Cooling Capacity (kuwTV_KL)</Title>
    <Description>Translates the ECU's internal cooling request into a 'relative cooling capacity' percentage that is sent to other control units (like the AC or Cluster) via CAN.</Description>
    <UseCase>Inter-module communication.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Leave stock.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Cooler refrigerant pressure characteristic (kuwKVM_KL)">
    <Title>Fan Speed - AC Pressure (kuwKVM_KL)</Title>
    <Description>Adjusts the cooling fan speed based on the refrigerant pressure in the air conditioning system. Higher AC pressure requires more airflow through the condenser.</Description>
    <UseCase>AC performance and protection.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Increase fan speed if AC performance is poor at a standstill.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="BIP Start-up max Battery voltage line (zmwBPAnIKL)">
    <Title>BIP Startup Voltage Limit (zmwBPAnIKL)</Title>
    <Description>Defines the maximum battery voltage allowed for BIP detection during the startup phase. It prevents electrical noise from high-voltage charging from corrupting the initial timing.</Description>
    <UseCase>Startup signal integrity.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Do not modify.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Kienzle tachograph route factor curve (fgwSF_KL)">
    <Title>Tachograph Route Factor (fgwSF_KL)</Title>
    <Description>A calibration line used to synchronize the vehicle speed signal with a Kienzle tachograph, ensuring accurate distance and speed recording for commercial vehicles.</Description>
    <UseCase>Commercial vehicle calibration.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Leave stock.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Conversion filter characteristic map (mrwFVHFIKL)">
    <Title>Torque Conversion Filter (mrwFVHFIKL)</Title>
    <Description>A filtering map used during the conversion of requested torque into injected quantity. It smooths out the calculation to prevent rapid, jittery changes in fueling.</Description>
    <UseCase>Signal smoothing.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Leave stock.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Oil temperature substitute value curve (anwO_LUrKL)">
    <Title>Oil Temp Fallback (anwO_LUrKL)</Title>
    <Description>Defines the substitute (limp home) value for engine oil temperature if the physical sensor fails. The value is typically modeled based on coolant temperature and time since start.</Description>
    <UseCase>Sensor failure management.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Leave stock.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Coolant setpoint - No climatronic correction (kmwKOR4_KL)">
    <Title>Coolant Setpoint - Base (kmwKOR4_KL)</Title>
    <Description>The base coolant temperature setpoint used when the Climatronic (AC) system is not requesting any specific thermal adjustments.</Description>
    <UseCase>Thermal management.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Modify to change the engine's base operating temperature.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="ARD limitation offset for limiting amount (mrwABegOKL)">
    <Title>ARD IQ Limit Offset (mrwABegOKL)</Title>
    <Description>Defines an offset applied to the injection quantity limits when the anti-jerk system is active. it ensures the ARD has enough 'room' to make adjustments without hitting other limiters.</Description>
    <UseCase>Anti-jerk stability.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Leave stock.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="EGR overrun shutdown upper threshold curve (arwREGSBN)">
    <Title>EGR Overrun Shutdown (arwREGSBN)</Title>
    <Description>Defines the engine speed threshold above which the EGR is deactivated during overrun (deceleration). This prevents exhaust gas from being trapped in the intake when the throttle is closed.</Description>
    <UseCase>Overrun management.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Leave stock.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="ARD Disturbance controller - Standard upper (mrwARDSoKL)">
    <Title>ARD Disturbance Upper Limit (mrwARDSoKL)</Title>
    <Description>Defines the upper correction limit for the ARD disturbance controller. This controller reacts to external shocks to the drivetrain (like hitting a pothole) to prevent bucking.</Description>
    <UseCase>Drivetrain stability.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Leave stock.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Pressure - Injection advance start selector (fnwSWST_KL)">
    <Title>SOI Startup Pressure Selector (fnwSWST_KL)</Title>
    <Description>Selects the appropriate injection advance for starting based on the current atmospheric pressure. It ensures the engine fires reliably at any altitude.</Description>
    <UseCase>Altitude starting calibration.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Leave stock.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Glowplug control - Afterglow period (gswGS_NGKL)">
    <Title>After-Glow Duration (gswGS_NGKL)</Title>
    <Description>Defines how long the glow plugs remain active after the engine has started. This 'after-glow' phase is critical for reducing smoke and noise during the first few minutes of cold operation.</Description>
    <UseCase>Cold start refinement.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Increase for smoother running in extremely cold weather.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Coolant run-on time ambient temp correction (kuwNLF_KL)">
    <Title>Fan Run-On - Ambient Correction (kuwNLF_KL)</Title>
    <Description>Adjusts the duration of the cooling fan run-on based on the outside air temperature. Hotter ambient air requires longer run-on times to dissipate heat.</Description>
    <UseCase>Post-shutdown cooling.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Increase for hot climates.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="PGS linearization (anwPGS_KL)">
    <Title>PGS Sensor Linearization (anwPGS_KL)</Title>
    <Description>Scales the signal from the redundant pedal sensor (PGS). The ECU compares this to the primary pedal sensor for safety monitoring.</Description>
    <UseCase>Safety monitoring.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Do not modify.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Glow intermediate glowing state time line (gswGS_T1ZG)">
    <Title>Intermediate Glow Duration (gswGS_T1ZG)</Title>
    <Description>Defines the duration of the 'intermediate' heating phase used in some glow plug control strategies to transition between pre-glow and after-glow.</Description>
    <UseCase>Glow plug life management.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Leave stock.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Limiter Smoke map selector (mrwBRA_KL)">
    <Title>Smoke Map Selector (mrwBRA_KL)</Title>
    <Description>This characteristic line selects which of the multiple Smoke Limiter maps is active. The selection is typically based on engine temperature or atmospheric pressure.</Description>
    <UseCase>Verifying active smoke maps.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Essential for ensuring your smoke limiter changes are actually being used by the ECU.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Oil temperature sensor linearization (anwOTF_KL)">
    <Title>Oil Temp Sensor Linearization (anwOTF_KL)</Title>
    <Description>Scales the raw signal from the engine oil temperature sensor into degrees Celsius.</Description>
    <UseCase>Calibration for custom sensors.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Leave stock.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Brake light switch linearization (anwBRE_KL)">
    <Title>Brake Switch Signal Scaling (anwBRE_KL)</Title>
    <Description>Scales the signal from the brake light switch. The ECU uses this to detect braking events for torque reduction and cruise control deactivation.</Description>
    <UseCase>Signal integrity.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Do not modify.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Atmospheric pressure correction (ldwLDBdPKL)">
    <Title>Boost Correction - Altitude (ldwLDBdPKL)</Title>
    <Description>A correction line that adjusts the boost target based on atmospheric pressure. It is a simpler version of the 3D Boost Limit Map.</Description>
    <UseCase>Altitude protection.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Leave stock.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Refrigerant pressure linearization (anwKMD_KL)">
    <Title>AC Pressure Sensor Linearization (anwKMD_KL)</Title>
    <Description>Scales the signal from the air conditioning refrigerant pressure sensor. This value is used to control the cooling fans and protect the AC compressor.</Description>
    <UseCase>AC system calibration.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Leave stock.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Analog/digital converter linearization (anwTAD_KL)">
    <Title>ADC Calibration (anwTAD_KL)</Title>
    <Description>The master calibration line for the ECU's internal Analog-to-Digital Converter. It ensures that all sensor voltages are interpreted correctly by the software.</Description>
    <UseCase>ECU hardware calibration.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Do not modify.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Voltage linearization - reference (anwREF_KL)">
    <Title>Reference Voltage Scaling (anwREF_KL)</Title>
    <Description>Scales the 5V reference voltage used by the ECU's sensors. It allows the ECU to compensate for minor fluctuations in the internal power supply.</Description>
    <UseCase>Signal accuracy.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Do not modify.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Voltage linearization - battery (anwUBAT_KL)">
    <Title>Battery Voltage Scaling (anwUBAT_KL)</Title>
    <Description>Scales the raw battery voltage signal. This value is used for BIP compensation, fan control, and alternator management.</Description>
    <UseCase>Electrical system monitoring.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Do not modify.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="Gate array response (edwGAR_KL)">
    <Title>Gate Array Diagnostic (edwGAR_KL)</Title>
    <Description>A diagnostic characteristic used to verify the response time and integrity of the ECU's internal gate array (custom logic chip).</Description>
    <UseCase>Hardware self-test.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Do not modify.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="RME Fuel IQ correction line (arwRME_KL)">
    <Title>Biodiesel IQ Correction (arwRME_KL)</Title>
    <Description>Adjusts the injected quantity based on the percentage of biodiesel detected in the fuel. Biodiesel has a lower energy density than standard diesel, so more fuel must be injected to achieve the same torque.</Description>
    <UseCase>Biodiesel tuning.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Increase values if running high concentrations of biodiesel to maintain performance.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>

  <Map Key="EGR Motor temp correction pre-injection (arwVEKORKL)">
    <Title>EGR Pre-Injection Correction (arwVEKORKL)</Title>
    <Description>Adjusts the EGR rate specifically during the pre-injection phase based on engine temperature. It helps reduce combustion noise and emissions during the warm-up period.</Description>
    <UseCase>Emissions and noise refinement.</UseCase>
    <TuningAdvice>Leave stock.</TuningAdvice>
  </Map>
</MapDescriptions>